<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\transforms\pp2html.xsl"?>

<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/commoncriteria/transforms/master/schemas/CCModule.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<Module target-products="File Encryption" xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1" xmlns:h="http://w.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="file encryption">  
  <PPReference>
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPVersion>2.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2019-02-05</PPPubDate>
      <Keywords>file encryption; encryption</Keywords>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  <RevisionHistory>
    <entry>
      <version>v 0.1</version>
      <date>2014-07-25</date>
      <subject>Initial Release</subject>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <version>v 1.0</version>
      <date>2014-11-10</date>
      <subject>Public release, incorporating comments received</subject>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <version>v 2.0</version>
      <date>2018-10-25</date>
      <subject>Enterprise Management, Requirement Clean Up, TDs Applied, Conversion to PP-Module</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview"> This PP-Module describes security
      requirements for an encryption product that is configurable for the data it encrypts and is
      intended to provide a minimal, baseline set of requirements that are targeted at mitigating
      well defined and described threats. However, this PP-Module is not complete in itself, but rather
      extends the Protection Profile for Application Software (<cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>). This
      introduction will describe the features of a compliant Target of Evaluation, and will also
      discuss how this PP-Module is to be used in conjunction with the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>. 
    
    File encryption is the process of encrypting individual files or sets of
    files (or volumes, or containers, etc.) on an end user device and permitting access to the
    encrypted data only after proper authentication is provided. Encryption products that
    conform to this PP-Module must render information inaccessible to anyone (or, in the case of other
    software on the machine, anything) that does not have the proper authentication credential.  
    The encrypted files may be on a local machine or may be sent to other devices.
    
      <h:br/> <h:br/>The foremost security objective of file
      encryption is to force an adversary to perform a cryptographic exhaust against a
      prohibitively large key space. Technology is changing at a rapid rate and the
      definition of mobile devices and traditional laptop/PC devices is quickly merging.
      Requirements can diverge slightly for Mobile vs Laptop/PC and the Evaluation Activities will
      describe any differences. Either of these use cases may be an enterprise managed file encryption client. 
      Some of the security functionality may be provided by the OE.
      The vendor is required to provide configuration guidance (AGD_PRE, AGD_OPE) to correctly install and 
      administer the TOE for every operational environment supported.<h:br/>  
      
      <h:br/> The data that is to be secured by the encryption product is encrypted using a File
      Encryption Key (FEK). A file encryptor may have zero or more Key Encryption Keys (KEKs) that
      protect (encrypt) the FEK. The number of keys and the types of keys may vary, but the design
      should follow one of the following models:<h:br/>
      <h:ol>
        <h:li>Condition a Password/Passphrase directly into a FEK</h:li>
        <h:li>Condition a Password/Passphrase into a KEK that is used to encrypt the randomly
          generated FEK directly or through a chaining of more than one KEK (these KEKs would be
          randomly generated).</h:li>
        <h:li>Use a software certificate or an external token to protect the FEK.</h:li>
      </h:ol> From a terminology standpoint, a KEK is either a symmetric key or an
      asymmetric key pair, and is used for both encryption and decryption of the
      FEK. If a distinction needs to be made between the public key (which encrypts the FEK) and
      the private key (which decrypts the FEK), this is done in the requirements and the evaluation
      activities below.<h:br/> <h:br/> 
      
      The TOE may be capable of supporting multiple users with different authorization factors, such that different users
      are able to use the same platform and not be able to read each other's encrypted files. The
      TOE may also support the ability for users to share an encrypted file without sharing an
      authorization factor, but this is not required. In order to claim this capability, the TOE must allow
      sharing of at least one encrypted resource among different users of the TOE who possess
      different authorization factors (e.g., two different smartcards, two different passwords, one
      using a password and another using a smartcard). If this capability is supported, then the ST
      author adds FIA_FCT_EXT.1.1.<h:br/> <h:br/> 
      
      <h:b>Authorization</h:b> <h:br/> One or more authorization factors must be established before data can
      be encrypted. This authorization factor(s) must be presented to the file encryption product
      in order for the user to request that the product decrypt the data. Authorization factors
      may be uniquely associated with individual users or may be associated with a community of
      users. The TOE is not required to support multiple types of authorization factors (e.g.,
      both passphrases and external authorization factors). If the ST author defines additional
      authorization factors, they must be fully documented and cannot diminish the strength of the
      passphrase and/or external token authorization factors. <h:br/> <h:br/>
      The password/passphrase authorization factors must be conditioned such that they are
      at least the same size (bit length) as the key they are protecting. 
      While this PP-Module does not dictate how these authentication factors are created, a
      good operational practice is for an administrator to generate the password or passphrase to
      ensure sufficient entropy.  Passphrases are preferred over passwords, since it is easier for users to remember and type in a sequence of
      words than recall a password and type in a long string of random characters.<h:br/><h:br/>
      
      <h:b>Administration</h:b> <h:br/> The base requirements of the TOE do not require the TOE to maintain an
      administrative role. Typically, administrators possess privilege to invoke
      functionality on the TOE that is not available to general users. For stand alone file encryption
      products, however, once the product is installed there should be little need for
      administrative involvement.  For enterprised managed file encryption products, the TOE may be remotely administered. <h:br/><h:br/>
      
      <h:b>Data Authentication (optional)</h:b> <h:br/> Because modification of ciphertext data
      for certain modes of encryption will enable unidentified plaintext manipulation, care must
      be taken by the TOE to mitigate against forged or maliciously modified ciphertext data. The
      PP-Module defines requirements for how the TOE must provide data authentication services, allowing
      the TOE to implement authenticated block cipher, keyed hash function or asymmetric signing
      features. Depending on the implementation, the TOE will be responsible for meeting at least
      one of the aforementioned requirements. In all cases, unsuccessful authentication of the
      data should not allow the user to see the decrypted ciphertext and notification should be
      provided to the user if such an event were to occur.<h:br/> <h:br/> A keyed hashing service may also
      be used to accomplish data authentication. This will involve using an approved keyed hashing
      service in accordance with FCS_COP.1(4) and proper protection of the File Authentication Key
      (FAK); the FAK being the secret value used as input to the keyed hash function. FAKs should
      be numerically different from the FEK, but will be protected in all of the same manners as
      the FEK. The primary requirement dictating implementation of data authentication using a
      keyed hash function is FDP_AUT_EXT.2.<h:br/> <h:br/> Lastly, asymmetric signing in conjunction with a
      secure hash function may be used to authenticate the data. The implementation must use an
      approved signing algorithm in accordance with FCS_COP.1(3) (from the <cite
        linkend="bibAppPP"/>) and an approved secure hashing function in accordance with
      FCS_COP.1(2) (from the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>). The primary requirement addressing data
      authentication via asymmetric signing is FDP_AUT_EXT.3. 
      
      The TOE and Its Supporting Environment:
      Since the TOE is purely a software solution, it must rely on the TOE Operational Environment (system
      hardware, firmware, and operating system) for its execution domain and its proper usage. The
      vendor is expected to provide sufficient installation and configuration instructions (for
      each platform listed in the ST) to identify Operational Environment(s) with the necessary
      features and to provide instructions for how to configure it correctly and securely. <h:br/> <h:br/>
      
      The PP-Module contains requirements (Section 4) that must be met by either the TOE or the platform
      on which it operates. A “platform” is defined as a separate entity whose functions may be
      used by the TOE, but is not part of the TOE. A third-party library used by the TOE is not
      considered part of the TOE’s “platform”, but (for instance) cryptographic functionality that
      is built into an Operating System on which the TOE executes can be considered part of the
      platform. <h:br/> <h:br/> 
      
      Likewise, an external entity (such as a smartcard) that performs
      cryptographic operations with respect to the FEK would also be considered a part of the “TOE
      Platform."<h:br/> The ST author will make the appropriate selection based on where
      that element is implemented. It is allowable for some elements in a component to be
      implemented by the TOE, while other elements in that same component may be implemented by
      the platform; in these cases, further guidance is given in the application notes and
      Supporting Documentation.<h:br/>  <h:br/> In some cases, the TOE vendor will have to provide specific
      configuration guidance for the Operational Environment to enable the TOE to meet its
      security objectives. These include:<h:br/> For non-mobile systems:<h:br/>
      <h:ul>
        <h:li>Instructions for how to configure the operational environment so that the system
          powers down completely after a period of user inactivity for every operating system that
          the product supports;</h:li>
        <h:li>Instructions for how to disable power managed state (e.g., hibernate/sleep)
          capabilities </h:li>
      </h:ul> For mobile systems:<h:br/>
      <h:ul>
        <h:li>Instructions for how to configure the operational environment to provide necessary
          behavior in support of TOE functionality when transition to a locked state after
          inactivity period and manually engaging the lock functionality.</h:li>
        <h:li>Instructions on how to configure the operational environment such that it is compliant
          with the Mobile Device Fundamentals Protection Profile.</h:li>
      </h:ul> It should be noted that if the TOE possesses the capability to correctly protect
      information in one or more of an underlying platform's power managed modes, they can use the
      FDP_PM_EXT.1 requirement in Appendix A.<h:br/><h:br/> Authorized users of the TOE are those users
      possessing valid authorization factors for the TOE. While some of these functions specified
      in the PP-Module might be considered “administrative” functions for other types of TOEs, for file
      encryption products it is the expectation that all of these functions can be performed by
      the end user of the software. 
    </section>
    
    <section id="glossary" title="Terms">
      <subsection title="Common Criteria Terms"> 
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr></term>
            <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr></term>
            <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category
              of products.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Protection Profile Module">PP</abbr></term>
            <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category
              of products.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Assurance Requirement">SAR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement to assure the security of the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr></term>
            <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a specific
              product.</description>
          </entry>
          
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr></term>
            <description>The product under evaluation. In this case, file encryption software and its
              supporting documentation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr></term>
            <description>The security functionality of the product under evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Security Policy">TSP</abbr></term>
            <description>The set of rules that regulate how assets are managed, protected and
              distributed within a TOE.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr></term>
            <description>A description of how a <abbr linkend="TOE"/> satisfies the SFRs in a <abbr
              linkend="ST"/>. </description>
          </entry>
          
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection title="Technical Terms">
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term>Administrator</term>
            <description> Authorized Users with higher privileges and typically handle configuration
              and management functions, such as configuring and updating the TOE. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Authorization factor (AF) </term>
            <description> a value submitted by the user, present on the host, or present on a
              separate protected hardware physical device used to establish that the user (and
              potentially the host) is in the community authorized to use the TOE. The authorization
              factors are used to generate the KEK. Note that these AFs are not used to establish
              the particular identity of the user. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Authorized User </term>
            <description> a user who has been provided Authorization factors by the administrator to
              use the TOE. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Data Encryption </term>
            <description> the process of encrypting all user data written to volatile memory.
            </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Deterministic Random Bit Generator (DRBG)</term>
            <description> a cryptographic algorithm that produces a sequence of bits from a secret
              initial seed value. Without knowledge of the seed value, the output sequence should be
              unpredictable up to the security level of the DRBG. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Entropy Source </term>
            <description> this cryptographic function provides a seed for a random bit generator by
              accumulating the outputs from one or more noise sources. The functionality includes a
              measure of the minimum work required to guess a given output and tests to ensure that
              the noise sources are operating properly. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>File/Set of files </term>
            <description> the user data that is selected to be encrypted, which can include
              individual file encryption (with a FEK per file) or a set of files encrypted with a
              single FEK. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>File Authentication Key (FAK) </term>
            <description> the secret value used as input when a keyed hash function is used to
              perform data authentication. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>File Encryption Key (FEK) </term>
            <description> the key that is used by the encryption algorithm to encrypt the selected
              user data on the host machine. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Key Chaining</term>
            <description>The method of using multiple layers of encryption keys to protect data. 
              A top layer key encrypts a lower layer key which encrypts the data; this method can have any number of layers.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Key Encryption Key (KEK) </term>
            <description> the key that is used to encrypt the FEK. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Keying Material </term>
            <description> the KEK, FEK, authorization factors and random numbers or any other values
              from which keys are derived. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Key Sanitization</term>
            <description> A method of sanitizing encrypted data by securely overwriting the key, as described in the key destruction requirement, that was encrypting the data. 
            </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Noise Source </term>
            <description> the component of an RBG that contains the non-deterministic,
              entropy-producing activity. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Operational Environment </term>
            <description> hardware and software that are outside the TOE boundary that support the
              TOE functionality and security policy, including the platform, its firmware, and
              the operating system. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Password </term>
            <description> A short string of characters used for authorization to the data on the
              device. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Passphrase</term>
            <description> A long string of characters that may be used for authorization to the data
              on the device. </description>
          </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>Primary Key Chain</term>
        <description>The direct key chain from the authorization factor to the FEK.</description>
      </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Random Bit Generator (RBG) </term>
            <description> a cryptographic function composed of an entropy source and DRBG that is
              invoked for random bits needed to produce keying material </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Sensitive Data </term>
            <description> Any data of which the compromise with respect to loss, misuse, or
              unauthorized access to or modification of could adversely affect the interest of the
              TOE user. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Shutdown </term>
            <description> power down or unintentional loss of power of the TOE or platform.
            </description>
          </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>Supplemental Key Chain</term>
        <description>Other key chains that add protection or functionality without compromising the security of the primary key chain.</description>
      </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>System files </term>
            <description> Files that reside on the host machine that are used in the operation of
              the file encryption software. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Temporary File - </term>
            <description> a file created by an application for short term storage of sensitive data.
            </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Trusted Host </term>
            <description> Source/destination host configured and maintained to provide the TOE with
              appropriate IT security commensurate with the value of the user data protected by the
              TOE. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Unauthorized User </term>
            <description> a user who has not been authorized to use the TOE and decrypt encrypted
              user data. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>User Data </term>
            <description> All data that originate on the host, or is derived from data that
              originate on the host, excluding system files and signed firmware updates from the TOE
              manufacturer. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Volatile memory </term>
            <description> memory that loses its content when power is turned off. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Zeroize</term>
            <description> this term is used to make a distinction between dereferencing a memory
              location and actively overwriting it with a constant. Keying material needs to be
              overwritten when it is no longer needed. </description>
          </entry>
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="complianttargets"> This PP-Module specifically
      addresses encryption of a set of data. This PP-Module addresses the primary threat that an
      unauthorized user will obtain access to a host machine containing encrypted information and be
      able to extract the sensitive data through the process of decryption. The Target of Evaluation
      (TOE) defined in this PP-Module is an encryption product that will inherently encrypt all of that
      data that the user selects to encrypt. For ease of explanation, “file” will frequently be used
      to refer to the object that is encrypted (however, it could be any number of things – folders,
      volumes, containers, etc.).<h:br/> <h:br/>  
    </section>
    
    <section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">
      <usecases>
      <usecase title="Unmanaged Endpoint" id="usecase1">
        <description>The traditional ability to encrypt files without external management and power down the machine and know the data is securely protected.</description>
      </usecase>
        <usecase title="Managed Endpoint" id="usecase2">
          <description>The traditional ability to encrypt files and power down the machine and know the data is securely protected, while communicating with an Enterprise Management server.</description>
        </usecase>
        <usecase title="Encrypted Distibution" id="usecase3">
          <description>The ability to encrypt a file on a machine and then send the encrypted file securely using a non-encrypted data in transit method.</description>
        </usecase>
      </usecases>
    </section>
  </chapter>
  
  <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="conf" boilerplate="no">
    <cclaims>
      <cclaim title="Conformance Statement">
        <description>
          <h:p>
            The Protection Profile for Application Software (<cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>)
            defines the baseline Security Functional Requirements (SFRs) and Security Assurance
            Requirements (SARs) for application software products. This <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> serves to
            extend the App PP baseline with additional SFRs and associated Evaluation Activities
            specific to an file encryption product.
            Evaluation Activities are the actions that the evaluator
            performs in order to determine a file encryption product's compliance to the SFRs.
          </h:p>
          <h:p>
             <h:b>Conformance Claims</h:b> <h:br/>
            This <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> conforms to Common Criteria <cite linkend="bibCC"/> for Information
            Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1, Revision 5. It is CC Part 2 extended and CC
            Part 3 conformant. In order to be conformant to this <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/>, the <abbr
              linkend="ST"/> must include all components in this <abbr linkend="PP-Module"/> and the
            associated App PP that are: <h:ul><h:li>unconditional (which are always required)</h:li>
              <h:li>selection-based (which are required when certain selections are chosen in the
                unconditional requirements)</h:li>
            </h:ul> and may include optional and/or objective components that are desirable but not
            required for conformance. 
          </h:p>
          <h:p>
            In accordance with CC Part 1, dependencies are not included when they are addressed by other SFRs.
            The evaluation activities provide adequate proof that any dependencies are also satisfied.
          </h:p>
          <h:b>Package Claims</h:b> <h:br/>
          This PP-Module does not claim conformance to any packages.
        </description>
      </cclaim>
    </cclaims>
  </chapter>
  
  <chapter title="Security Problem Description" id="spd"> The primary asset that is being protected
    is the sensitive user data stored on a system. The threat model thus focuses on a host machine
    that has been compromised by an unauthorized user. This section addresses threats to the TOE
    only. 
    
    <section title="Threats" id="threats"> A threat consists of a threat agent, an asset, and
      an adverse action of that threat agent on that asset. The model in this PP-Module only addresses
      risks that arise from the host machine being compromised by an unauthorized user.<h:br/><h:br/>
      
      For this PP-Module, the TOE is not expected to defend against all threats related to malicious software
      that may reside in user data files. For instance, the TOE is not responsible for detecting
      malware in the data selected by the user for encryption (that is a responsibility of the host
      environment). Once the file encryption product is operational in a host system, the threats
      against the data from potentially malicious software on the host are also not in the threat
      model of this PP-Module. For example, there are no requirements in this PP-Module addressing a malicious
      host capturing a password-based authorization factor, nor a malicious process reading the
      memory of an application program that is operating on a decrypted file.<h:br/><h:br/> 
      
      Note that this PP-Module
      does not repeat the threats identified in the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>, though they all
      apply given the conformance and hence dependence of this PP-Module on the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>.
      <h:br/><h:br/>
      
      Note also that while the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/> contains only threats to the ability of
      the TOE to provide its security functions, this PP-Module focuses on threats to resources in the
      operational environment. Together the threats of the App PP and those defined in this PP-Module define
      the comprehensive set of security threats addressed by a file encryption TOE. 
      <threats>
        <threat id="T.UNAUTHORIZED_DATA_ACCESS">
          <description>
            <h:b>Unauthorized Data Access:</h:b> An attacker has access to an account that is not permitted to decrypt 
          files or has no access and uses forensic tools for examination.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.PROTECT_DATA">
            <rationale>The threat T.UNAUTHORIZED_DATA_ACCESS is countered by O.PROTECT_DATA as this
              provides for encyption of data.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.MANAGEMENT_ACCESS">
          <description>
            <h:b>Management Access:</h:b> File encryption products require security management functions be restricted to authorized users
          and cover critical security functionality.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.MANAGE">
            <rationale>The threat T.UNAUTHORIZED_DATA_ACCESS is countered by O.MANAGE as this
              ensures proper management functionality.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.KEYING_MATERIAL_COMPROMISE">
          <description>
            <h:b>Compromise of Keying Material:</h:b> An attacker exploits a weakness in the random number generation, 
            plaintext keys, and other keying material to decrypt an encrypted file. </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.KEY_MATERIAL_PROTECTION">
            <rationale>The threat T.KEYING_MATERIAL_COMPROMISE is countered by O.KEY_MATERIAL_PROTECTION as this
              provides for protection of keys.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.UNSAFE_AUTHFACTOR_VERIFICATION">
          <description>
            <h:b>Flawed Authentication Factor Verification:</h:b> An attacker exploits a flaw in the validation or conditioning of 
            the authorization factor. </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.SAFE_AUTHFACTOR_VERIFICATION">
            <rationale>The threat T.UNSAFE_AUTHFACTOR_VERIFICATION is countered by O.SAFE_AUTHFACTOR_VERIFICATION as this
              provides for properly supported authentication factors.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.KEYSPACE_EXHAUST">
          <description>
            <h:b>Brute Force Attack:</h:b> An attacker is able to brute force the keyspace of the algorithms used.
          </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.FEK_SECURITY">
            <rationale>The threat T.KEYSPACE_EXHAUST is countered by O.FEK_SECURITY as this
              makes brute force attacks infeasible.</rationale>
            </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.PLAINTEXT_COMPROMISE">
          <description>
            <h:b>Plaintext Compromise:</h:b> An attacker is able to uncover plaintext remains with forensic tools.
          </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.WIPE_MEMORY">
            <rationale>The threat T.PLAINTEXT_COMPROMISE is countered by O.WIPE_MEMORY as this
              provides data cleanup.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
      
      </threats>
    </section>

    <section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
      <assumptions>
          <assumption id="A.AUTH_FACTOR">
            <description>An authorized user will be responsible for ensuring that all externally
              derived authorization factors have sufficient strength and entropy to reflect the
              sensitivity of the data being protected. This can apply to password- or
              passphrase-based, ECC CDH, and RSA authorization factors.</description>
            <objective-refer ref="OE.AUTHORIZATION_FACTOR_STRENGTH">
              <rationale>The operational environment objective OE.AUTHORIZATION_FACTOR_STRENGTH is realized through A.AUTH_FACTOR.</rationale>
            </objective-refer>
          </assumption>
          <assumption id="A.EXTERNAL_FEK_PROTECTION">
            <description>External entities that implement ECC CDH or RSA that are used to encrypt
              and decrypt a FEK have the following characteristics: <h:br/>meet National requirements
              for the cryptographic mechanisms implemented; <h:br/>require authentication via a pin or
              other mechanisms prior to allowing access to protected information (the decrypted FEK,
              or the private key); <h:br/>implement anti-hammer provisions where appropriate (for
              example, when a pin is the authentication factor). </description>
            <objective-refer ref="OE.STRONG_ENVIRONMENT_CRYPTO">
              <rationale>The operational environment objective OE.STRONG_ENVIRONMENT_CRYPTO is realized through A.EXTERNAL_FEK_PROTECTION.</rationale>
              </objective-refer>
          </assumption>
          <assumption id="A.SHUTDOWN">
            <description>An authorized user will not leave the machine in a mode where sensitive
              information persists in non-volatile storage.</description>
            <objective-refer ref="OE.POWER_SAVE">
              <rationale>The operational environment objective OE.POWER_SAVE is realized through A.SHUTDOWN.</rationale>
            </objective-refer>
          </assumption>
          <assumption id="A.STRONG_OE_CRYPTO">
            <description>All cryptography implemented in the Operational Environment and used by the
              TOE will meet the requirements listed in this PP-Module. This includes
              generation of external token authorization factors by a RBG.</description>
            <objective-refer ref="OE.STRONG_ENVIRONMENT_CRYPTO">
              <rationale>The operational environment objective OE.STRONG_ENVIRONMENT_CRYPTO is realized through A.STRONG_OE_CRYPTO.</rationale>
            </objective-refer>
          </assumption>
          <assumption id="A.FILE_INTEGRITY ">
            <description>When the file is in transit, it is not modified, otherwise if that
              possibility exists, the appropriate selections in Appendix B are chosen for Data
              Authentication.</description>
            <objective-refer ref="OE.STRONG_ENVIRONMENT_CRYPTO">
              <rationale>The operational environment objective OE.STRONG_ENVIRONMENT_CRYPTO is realized through A.STRONG_OE_CRYPTO.</rationale>
            </objective-refer>
          </assumption>
        </assumptions>
      </section>
     <section title="Organizational Security Policies" id="OSPs">
      There are no Organizational Security Policies for the PP-Module.
       </section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Security Objectives" id="obj"> 
    The Security Problem described in
    <secref linkend="spd"/> will be addressed by a combination of cryptographic capabilities. Compliant TOEs
    will provide security functionality that addresses threats to the TOE. The following subsections provide a description of the
    security objectives required to meet the threats previously discussed. The
    description of these security objectives are in addition to that described in the <cite
      linkend="bibAppPP"/>.<h:br/> 
    <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="objtoe"> 
      <SOs>
        <SO id="O.KEY_MATERIAL_PROTECTION">
          <description>
            <h:b>Protection of Key Material:</h:b> The TOE must ensure that sensative plaintext key material used
            in performing its operations is cleared once it is no longer needed. Key material must
            be identified; its use and intermediate storage areas must also be identified; and then
            those storage areas must be cleared in a timely manner and without interruptions. For
            example, authorization factors are only needed until the KEK is formed; at that point,
            volatile memory areas containing the authorization factors should be cleared. </description>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.4"/>
          <component-refer ref="FPT_KYP_EXT.1"/>
          
          <consistency-rationale>
            This objective is consistent with <base-name/>.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.FEK_SECURITY">
          <description>
            <h:b>Encryption Using a Strong FEK and KEK:</h:b> In order to ensure that brute force
            attacks are infeasible, the TOE must ensure that the cryptographic strength of the keys
            and authorization factors used to generate and protect the keys is sufficient to
            withstand attacks in the near-to-mid-term future. Password/passphrase complexity and
            conditioning requirements are also levied to help ensure that a brute force attack
            against these authorization factors (when used) has a similar level of resistance.
          </description>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(1)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(5)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(7)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_KDF_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(8)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_VAL_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_IV_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_KYC_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_CKM_EXT.1(1)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_SMC_EXT.1 "/>
          
          <consistency-rationale>
            This objective is consistent with <base-name/>.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.WIPE_MEMORY">
          <description>
            <h:b>Removal of Plaintext Data:</h:b> To address the threat of unencrypted copies of data
            being left in non-volatile memory or temporary files where it may be accessed by an
            unauthorized user, the TOE will ensure that plaintext data it creates is securely erased
            when no longer needed. The TOE’s responsibility is to utilize the appropriate TOE
            platform method for secure erasure, but the TOE is not responsible for verifying that
            the secure erasure occurred as this will be the responsibility of the TOE platform. </description>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_PRT_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_PRT_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_PRT_EXT.3"/>
          
          
          <consistency-rationale>
            This objective is consistent with <base-name/>.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.PROTECT_DATA">
          <description>
            <h:b>Protection of Data:</h:b> The TOE will encrypt data to protect the data from
            unauthorized access. Encrypting the file or set of files will protect the user data even
            when low-level tools that bypass operating system protections such as discretionary and
            mandatory access controls are available to an attacker. Users that are authorized to
            access the data must provide authorization factors to the TOE in order for the data to
            be decrypted and provided to the user. </description>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_COP.1(1)"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_IV_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_PRT_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_PRT_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_PM_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_PRT_EXT.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_PRT_EXT.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_FCT_EXT.1"/>
          
          <consistency-rationale>
            This objective is consistent with <base-name/>.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
        <SO id="O.SAFE_AUTHFACTOR_VERIFICATION">
          <description>
            <h:b>Safe Authentication Factor Verification:</h:b> In order to avoid exposing information
            that would allow an attacker to compromise or weaken any factors in the chain keys
            generated or protected by the authorization factors, the TOE will verify the valid
            authorization factor prior to the FEK being used to decrypt the data being
            protected.
          </description>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_VAL_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_AUT_EXT.1"/>
          
          <consistency-rationale>
            This objective is consistent with <base-name/>.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
      
        <SO id="O.MANAGE">
          <description>The TOE will provide all the functions and facilities necessary to support
            the authorized administrators in their management of the security of the TOE, and
            restrict these functions and facilities from unauthorized use.</description>
          <component-refer ref="FMT_SMF.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="FMT_MEC_EXT.1"/>
          
          <consistency-rationale>
            This objective is consistent with <base-name/>.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
      </SOs>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment" id="objenv">
      <SOs>
        <SO id="OE.AUTHORIZATION_FACTOR_STRENGTH">
          <description>An authorized user will be responsible for ensuring that all externally
            derived authorization factors have sufficient strength and entropy to reflect the
            sensitivity of the data being protected. This can apply to password- or
            passphrase-based, ECC CDH, and RSA authorization factors.</description>
          <component-refer ref="FIA_AUT_EXT.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_VAL_EXT.1"/>
          <consistency-rationale>
            This objective is consistent with <base-name/>.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
        <SO id="OE.POWER_SAVE">
          <description>The non-mobile operational environment must be configurable so that there
            exists at least one mechanism that will cause the system to enter a safe power state (A.SHUTDOWN). Any
            such mechanism (e.g., sleep, hibernate) that does not conform to this requirement must
            be capable of being disabled. <h:br/> The mobile operational environment must be
            configurable such that there exists at least one mechanism that will cause the system to
            lock upon a period of time. </description>
          <component-refer ref="FDP_PRT_EXT.1"/>
          <consistency-rationale>
            This objective is consistent with <base-name/>.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
        <SO id="OE.STRONG_ENVIRONMENT_CRYPTO">
          <description>The Operating environment will provide a cryptographic function capability
            that is commensurate with the requirements and capabilities of the TOE.</description>
          <component-refer ref="FCS_KYC_EXT.1"/>
          <consistency-rationale>
            This objective is consistent with <base-name/>.
          </consistency-rationale>
        </SO>
       </SOs>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Security Objectives Rationale" id="SOR"/>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">
    <base-pp 
      product="application"
      name="Application Software 1.3" short="App" 
      url="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=394&amp;id=394"
      xmlurl="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/commoncriteria/application/c51970161d3a47fe8a7c23552f372745a638ba7d/input/application.xml">
      
      <sec-func-req-dir>
The TOE is expected to rely on some of the security functions implemented by the application as a whole and evaluated against the AppPP.
The following sections describe any modifications that the ST author must make to the SFRs defined in the Base-PP in addition to what is mandated by section 5.2.       
      </sec-func-req-dir>
      <modified-sfrs>
      <f-component id="FMT_SMF.2" name="Specification of File Encryption Management Functions">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FMT_SMF.2.1">
            <title>The TSF shall be capable of performing the following management functions:
                <selectables linebreak="yes">
                  <selectable>configure password/passphrase complexity setting</selectable>
                  <selectable>configure cryptographic functionality</selectable>
                  <selectable>change authentication factors</selectable>
                  <selectable>perform a cryptograph erase of the data by the destruction of FEKs or KEKs protecting the FEKs as described in FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1</selectable>
                  <selectable>configure the number of failed validation attempts required to trigger corrective behavior  </selectable>
                  <selectable>configure the corrective behavior to issue in the event of an excessive number of failed validation attempts</selectable>
                  <selectable><assignable>other management functions provided by the TSF</assignable></selectable>
              </selectables>
            </title>
            <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to express the management
              capabilities that may be included in the TOE. Several common options are given:<h:br/>
              <h:ul>
                <h:li>If the TOE provides for a password/passphrase complexity setting, then
                  “configure password/passphrase complexity setting” will be included, and the
                  specifics of the functionality offered can either be written from the requirement
                  as bullets points, or included in the TSS.</h:li>
                <h:li>If the TOE provides configurability of the cryptographic functions (for example,
                  key size of the FEK)—even if the configuration is the form of parameters that may
                  be passed to cryptographic functionality implement on the TOE platform--then
                  “configure cryptographic functionality” will be included, and the specifics of the
                  functionality offered can either be written in this requirement as bullet points,
                  or included in the TSS.</h:li>
                <h:li>If the TOE uses stored FEKS or KEKs(the FEK is not directly derived from a password)
                  , then “perform a cryptograph erase of the data by the destruction of FEKs or KEKs protecting the FEKs as described in FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1” will be included.</h:li>
                <h:li>If “other management functions” are assigned, a validation authority must be
                  consulted to ensure the evaluation activities and other functionality requirements
                  that may be needed are appropriately specified so that the ST can claim
                  conformance to this PP-Module.</h:li>
              </h:ul>
              <h:br/>
              This list is in addition to the list of functions, SMF_FMT.1 in the Application Software Protection Profile.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
               The ST author should combine the selections with those in the FMT_SMF.1 requirement in the Application Software PP to 
              form a single FMT_SMF SFR in the ST.
              
              The evaluation activities for this component will be driven by the selections
              made by the ST author. This section describes evaluation activities for all possible
              selections in an ST; it should be understood that if a capability is not selected in
              the ST, the noted evaluation activity does not need to be performed. The following
              sections are divided up into “Required Activities” and “Conditional Activities” for
              ease of reference. 
              
              If password or passphrase authorization factors are implemented by the TOE, then the appropriate 
              “change” selection must be included.
              
              If the TOE provides configurability of the cryptographic functions (for example, key size of the FEK)—
              even if the configuration is the form of parameters that may be passed to cryptographic functionality implemented on
              the TOE platform--then “configure cryptographic functionality” will be included, and the specifics 
              of the functionality offered can either be written in this requirement as bullet points, or included in the TSS.
              
              If “other management functions” are assigned, a validation authority must be consulted to ensure the 
              evaluation activities and other functionality requirements that may be needed are appropriately 
              specified so that the ST can claim conformance to this PP-Module.
              
              <TSS/>
              <h:b>Conditional Activities:</h:b> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it
              describes the sequence of activities that take place from an implementation
              perspective when this activity is performed (for example, how it determines which
              resources are associated with the KEK, the decryption and re-encryption process), and
              ensure that the KEK and FEK are not exposed during this change. <h:br/>
              <h:b>Cryptographic Configuration:</h:b> None for this requirement. <h:br/>
              
              <Guidance/>
              <h:b>Conditional Activities:</h:b> The evaluator shall examine the Operational Guidance to
              ensure that it describes how the password/passphrase-based authorization factor is to
              be changed. <h:br/>
              <h:b>Cryptographic Configuration:</h:b> The evaluator shall determine from the TSS for
              other requirements (FCS_*, FDP_PRT_EXT, FIA_AUT_EXT) what portions of the
              cryptographic functionality are configurable. The evaluator shall then review the AGD
              documentation to determine that there are instructions for manipulating all of the
              claimed mechanisms. 
              <Tests/>
              <h:b>Cryptographic Erase:</h:b> If the TOE uses stored FEKS or KEKs, the evaluator shall 
              examine the key chain to determine that the keys destroyed by a cryptographic erase will result in the data becoming unrecoverable.
              Testing for this activity is performed for other components in this PP-Module. 
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
      </modified-sfrs>
      <con-toe></con-toe>
      <con-sec-prob></con-sec-prob>
      <con-obj></con-obj>
      <con-op-en></con-op-en>
    </base-pp>
    
    <man-sfrs>
      <description>
The following section describes the SFRs that must be satisfied by any TOE that claims conformance to this PP-Module. 
      </description>
      <subsection title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)" id="fcs">
        <f-component id="FCS_CKM_EXT.2" name="Cryptographic key generation (FEK)">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.2.1">
            <title> The TSF shall 
              <selectables>
                <selectable> accept FEK from an enterprise management server</selectable>
                <selectable> generate FEK cryptographic keys <h:br/>
                  <selectables linebreak="yes">
                    <selectable> using a Random Bit Generator as specified in FCS_RBG_EXT.1 (from the AS
                      PP) and with entropy corresponding to the security strength of AES key sizes of
                      <selectables>
                        <selectable>128 bit</selectable>
                        <selectable>256 bit</selectable>
                      </selectables></selectable>
                    <selectable> derived from a password/passphrase that is conditioned as defined in FCS_CKM_EXT.1(1) </selectable>
                  </selectables>
                </selectable>
              </selectables>,
            </title>
            <!--Removed as repetative.
            <note role="application"> For the first selection, the TOE may accept FEKS from an file encryption enterprise managment server.
              For the second selection, the key generation capability of the TOE uses a RBG implemented on the TOE device (FCS_RBG_EXT.1 from the <cite
                linkend="bibAppPP"/>)or the key is derived from the conditioning of a password/passphrase. The enterprise management server is described in the 
              File Encryption Enterprise Management PP-Module.<h:br/>
            </note>
            -->
          </f-element>
           
          
          <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.2.2">
            <title>The TSF shall use a unique FEK for each file (or set of files) using the
              mechanism on the client as specified in FCS_CKM_EXT.2.1.</title>
           
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/> 
              FCS_CKM_EXT.2.1: The evaluator shall review the TSS to determine that a
              description covering how and when the FEKs are generated exists. The description must
              cover all environments on which the TOE is claiming conformance, and include any
              preconditions that must exist in order to successfully generate the FEKs. The evaluator shall verify 
              that the description of how the FEKs are generated is consistent with
              the instructions in the AGD guidance, and any differences that arise from different
              platforms are taken into account. <h:br/> <h:br/> 
              
              Conditional: <h:br/> 
              If using a RBG was selected the evaluator verify the TSS to determine that it describes how the functionality
              described by FCS_RBG_EXT.1 (from the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>) is invoked to
              generate FEK. To the extent possible from the description of the RBG functionality in
              FCS_RBG_EXT.1 (from the App PP), the evaluator shall determine that the key size being
              requested is identical to the key size and mode to be used for the
              decryption/encryption of the user data (FCS_COP.1(1)).  <h:br/> <h:br/> 
              
              Conditional: <h:br/>               
              If derived from a password/password is selected the examination of the TSS section is performed as
              part of FCS_CKM_EXT.1(1) evaluation activities. <h:br/>  <h:br/> 
              
              
              FCS_CKM_EXT.2.2: The evaluator shall
              verify the TSS describes how a FEK is used for a protected
              resource and associated with that resource. The evaluator confirms that—per this description—the
              FEK is unique per resource (file or set of files) and that the FEK is established using
              the mechanisms specified in FCS_CKM_EXT.2.1). <h:br/> 
              
              <Guidance/> The evaluator shall review the
              instructions in the AGD guidance to determine that any explicit actions that need to
              be taken by the user to establish a FEK exist—taking into account any differences that
              arise from different platforms—and are consistent with the description in the TSS.
              
              
              <Tests/> None. 
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      
        
        
       
        
        
        <f-component id="FCS_CKM_EXT.4" name="Extended: Cryptographic Key Destruction">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1">
            <title>The TSF shall destroy cryptographic keys in accordance with a specified cryptographic key destruction method 
              <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable> For volatile memory, the destruction shall be executed by a
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>single overwrite consisting of 
                      <selectables>
                        <selectable>a pseudo-random pattern using the TSF's RBG</selectable>
                        <selectable>zeros</selectable>
                        <selectable>ones</selectable>
                        <selectable>new value of a key</selectable>
                        <selectable><assignable>any value that does not contain any CSP</assignable></selectable>
                      </selectables>
                    </selectable>
                    <selectable>removal of power to the memory</selectable>
                    <selectable>destruction of reference to the key directly followed by a request for garbage collection</selectable>
                  </selectables>
                </selectable>
                <selectable> For non-volatile memory that consists of 
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>destruction of all key encrypting keys protecting the target key according to FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1,
                      where none of the KEKs protecting the target key are derived
                    </selectable>
                    <selectable> the invocation of an interface provided by the underlying platform that
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>logically addresses the storage location of the key and performs a
                      <selectables>
                        <selectable>single</selectable>
                        <selectable><assignable>ST author defined multi-pass</assignable></selectable>
                      </selectables>
                      overwrite consisting of 
                      <selectables>
                        <selectable>a pseudo-random pattern using the TSF's RBG</selectable>
                        <selectable>zeros</selectable>
                        <selectable>ones</selectable>
                        <selectable>new value of a key</selectable>
                        <selectable><assignable>any value that does not contain any CSP</assignable></selectable>
                      </selectables>
                    </selectable>
                    <selectable>instructs the underlying platform to destory the abstraction the represents the key</selectable>
                  </selectables>
                    </selectable>
                  </selectables>
                 
                  
                </selectable>
              </selectables>
            </title>
            <note role="application">The interface referenced in the requirement could take different forms, the most likely 
              of which is an application programming interface to an OS kernel. There may be various levels of abstraction visible. 
              For instance, in a given implementation that overwrites a key stored in non-volatile memory, the application may have 
              access to the file system details and may be able to logically address specific memory locations. In another 
              implementation that instructs the underlying platform to destroy the representation of a key stored in non-volatile 
              memory, the application may simply have a handle to a resource and can only ask the platform to delete the resource, 
              as may be the case with a platforms secure key store. The latter implementation should only be used for the most 
              restricted access. The level of detail to which the TOE has access will be reflected in the TSS section of the ST. 
              Several selections allow assignment of a 'value that does not contain any CSP'. This means that the TOE uses some 
              other specified data not drawn from a source that may contain key material or reveal information about key material, 
              and not being any of the particular values listed as other selection options. The point of the phrase 'does not contain 
              any CSP' is to ensure that the overwritten data is carefully selected, and not taken from a general 'pool' that might 
              contain current or residual data that itself requires confidentiality protection.<h:br/>

              For the selection “destruction of all key encrypting keys protecting target key according to FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1, where 
              none of the KEKs protecting the target key are derived”, a key can be considered destroyed by destroying the key that 
              protects the key. If a key is wrapped or encrypted it is not necessary to “overwrite” that key, overwriting the key 
              that is used to wrap or encrypt the key used to encrypt/decrypt data, using the appropriate method for the memory 
              type involved, will suffice. For example, if a product uses a Key Encryption Key (KEK) to encrypt a Data Encryption 
              Key (DEK), destroying the KEK using one of the methods in FCS_CKM_EXT.4 is sufficient, since the DEK would no longer 
              be usable (of course, presumes the DEK is still encrypted and the KEK cannot be recovered or re-derived.). </note>
            
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/>
              The evaluator examines the TSS to ensure it describes how the keys are managed in volatile memory. 
              This description includes details of how each identified key is introduced into volatile memory (e.g. by derivation 
              from user input, or by unwrapping a wrapped key stored in non-volatile memory) and how they are overwritten.<h:br/>
              
              The evaluator shall check to ensure the TSS lists each type of key that is stored in in non-volatile memory, and 
              identifies how the TOE interacts with the underlying platform to manage keys (e.g., store, retrieve, destroy). 
              The description includes details on the method of how the TOE interacts with the platform, including an identification 
              and description of the interfaces it uses to manage keys (e.g., file system APIs, platform key store APIs).<h:br/>
              
              The evaluator examines the interface description for each different media type to ensure that the 
              interface supports the selection(s) and description in the TSS.<h:br/>
              
              If the ST makes use of the open assignment and fills in the type of pattern that is used, the evaluator 
              examines the TSS to ensure it describes how that pattern is obtained and used. The evaluator shall 
              verify that the pattern does not contain any CSPs.<h:br/>
              
              The evaluator shall check that the TSS identifies any configurations or 
              circumstances that may not strictly conform to the key destruction requirement.<h:br/>
              
              If the selection “destruction of all key encrypting keys protecting target key according to FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1, 
              where none of the KEKs protecting the target key are derived” is included the evaluator shall examine the TOE’s 
              keychain in the TSS and identify each instance when a key is destroyed by this method. In each instance the evaluator 
              shall verify all keys capable of decrypting the target key are destroyed in accordance with a specified key destruction 
              method in FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1 The evaluator shall verify that all of the keys capable of decrypting the target key are not 
              able to be derived to reestabish the keychain after their destruction. <h:br/>
                            
              <Guidance/> There are a variety of concerns that may prevent or delay key destruction in some cases.
              
              The evaluator shall check that the guidance documentation identifies configurations or circumstances that may 
              not strictly conform to the key destruction requirement, and that this description is consistent with the 
              relevant parts of the TSS and any other relevant Required Supplementary Information.
              
              The evaluator shall check that the guidance documentation provides guidance on situations where key 
              destruction may be delayed at the physical layer and how such situations can be avoided or mitigated if possible.
              
              Some examples of what is expected to be in the documentation are provided here. 
              
              When the TOE does not have full access to the physical memory, it is possible that the storage may be implementing 
              wear-leveling and garbage collection. This may create additional copies of the key that are logically inaccessible 
              but persist physically. In this case, to mitigate this the drive should support the TRIM command and implements 
              garbage collection to destroy these persistent copies when not actively engaged in other tasks.
              
              Drive vendors implement garbage collection in a variety of different ways, as such there is a variable amount of time 
              until data is truly removed from these solutions. There is a risk that data may persist for a longer amount of time 
              if it is contained in a block with other data not ready for erasure. To reduce this risk, the operating system and 
              file system of the OE should support TRIM, instructing the non-volatile memory to erase copies via garbage collection 
              upon their deletion. If a RAID array is being used, only set-ups that support TRIM are utilized. If the drive is 
              connected via PCI-Express, the operating system supports TRIM over that channel.
              
              The drive should be healthy and contains minimal corrupted data and should be end of lifed before a significant 
              amount of damage to drive health occurs, this minimizes the risk that small amounts of 
              potentially recoverable data may remain in damaged areas of the drive.
              
              <Tests/>
              These tests are only for key destruction provided by the application, test 2 does not apply to any keys using the selection "new value of a key": 
              <testlist>
                <test>Applied to each key held in volatile memory and subject to destruction by overwrite by the 
                  TOE (whether or not the value is subsequently encrypted for storage in volatile or non-volatile memory). 
                  In the case where the only selection made for the key destruction method was removal of power, then this test is unnecessary. 
                  
                  The evaluator shall:
                  
                  Record the value of the key in the TOE subject to clearing.
                  
                  Cause the cause the TOE or the underlying platform to dump to perform a normal cryptographic processing with the key from Step #1.
                  
                  Cause the TOE to clear the key.
                  
                  Cause the TOE to stop the execution but not exit.
                  
                  Cause the TOE to dump the entire memory of the TOE into a binary file.
                  
                  Search the content of the binary file created in Step #5 for instances of the known key value from Step #1.
                  
                  Steps 1-6 ensure that the complete key does not exist anywhere in volatile memory. If a copy is found, then the test fails.</test>
                
                <test>[Contitional] If new value of a key is selected this test does not apply. 
                  Applied to each key held in non-volatile memory and subject to destruction by the TOE. 
                  The evaluator shall use special tools (as needed), provided by the TOE developer if necessary, to ensure the tests function as intended.
                  
                  Identify the purpose of the key and what access should fail when it is deleted. (e.g. the data encryption key being deleted would cause data decryption to fail.)
                  
                  Cause the TOE to clear the key.
                  
                  Have the TOE attempt the functionality that the cleared key would be necessary for.
                  
                  The test succeeds if step 3 fails.</test>
                  
                Tests 3 and 4 do not apply for the selection instructing the underlying platform to destroy the representation of the key, as the TOE has no visibility into the inner workings and completely relies on the underlying platform.
                
                <test>Applied to each key held in non-volatile memory and subject to destruction by overwrite by the TOE. The evaluator shall use a tool that provides a logical view of the media (e.g., MBR file system):
                  
                  Record the value of the key in the TOE subject to clearing.
                  
                  Cause the TOE to perform a normal cryptographic processing with the key from Step #1.
                  
                  Cause the TOE to clear the key.
                  
                  Search the logical view that the key was stored in for instances of the known key value from Step #1. If a copy is found, then the test fails. </test>
                  
                <test>Applied to each key held in non-volatile memory and subject to destruction by overwrite by the TOE. The evaluator shall use a tool that provides a logical view of the media:
                  
                  Record the logical storage location of the key in the TOE subject to clearing.
                  
                  Cause the TOE to perform a normal cryptographic processing with the key from Step #1.
                  
                  Cause the TOE to clear the key.
                  
                  Read the logical storage location in Step #1 of non-volatile memory to ensure the appropriate pattern is utilized.
                  
                  The test succeeds if correct pattern is used to overwrite the key in the memory location. If the pattern is not found the test fails.</test>
              </testlist>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
          
          <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1(1)">
            <title>The TSF shall destroy all keys and key material when no longer needed.</title>
            
            <note role="application">Application Note: Keys, including intermediate keys and key material that are no longer
              needed are destroyed by using an approved method, FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1. Examples of keys are
              intermediate keys, submasks. There may be instances where keys or key material
              that are contained in persistent storage are no longer needed and require destruction. 
              Base on their implementation, vendors will explain when certain keys are no longer needed. There
              are multiple situations in which key material is no longer necessary, for example, a wrapped
              key may need to be destroyed when a password is changed. However, there are instances
              when keys are allowed to remain in memory, for example, a device identification key. If a
              PIN was used for a SmartCard and managed by the TOE, ensuring that the PIN was properly destroyed shall be addressed.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/> or KMD (Key Management Description may be used if necessary details describe proprietary information)            
              The evaluator shall verify the TSS  includes a key lifecycle, that includes a
              description where key material reside, how the key material is used, how it is
              determined that keys and key material are no longer needed, and how the material is
              destroyed once it is not needed and that the documentation in the follows
              FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1 for the destruction.
              
                            
              <Guidance/> None.
              
              <Tests/> None.
              
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
       
      
        
        
        
        
        <f-component id="FCS_VAL_EXT.1" name="Extended: Validation">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FCS_VAL_EXT.1.1 ">
            <title>The TSF shall perform validation of the 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>submask</selectable>
                <selectable>intermediate key</selectable>
              </selectables> using the following method(s): 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>key wrap as specified in FCS_COP.1(5)</selectable>
                <selectable>hash the 
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>submask</selectable>
                    <selectable>intermediate key</selectable>
                    <selectable>FEK</selectable> 
                  </selectables>as specified in FCS_COP.1.1(2)and compare it to a stored hashed </selectable> 
                <selectable>decrypt a known value using the 
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>submask</selectable>
                    <selectable>intermediate key</selectable>
                    <selectable>FEK</selectable>
                  </selectables> as specified in FCS_COP.1(1) and compare it against a stored known value</selectable>
              </selectables> 
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="FCS_VAL_EXT.1.2">
            <title>The TSF shall require validation as specified in FCS_VAL_EXT.1.1 prior to decrypting any FEK.</title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="FCS_VAL_EXT.1.3">
            <title>The TSF shall 
              <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable>[perform a key destruction of the FEK(s)] upon a configurable number of consecutive failed validation attempts</selectable>
                <selectable>institute a delay such that only <assignable>ST author specified number of attempts</assignable> can be made within a 24 hour period</selectable>
                <selectable>block validation after <assignable>ST author specified number of attempts</assignable> of consecutive failed validation attempts</selectable>
                <selectable>require power cycle/reset the TOE after <assignable>ST author specified number of attempts</assignable> of consecutive failed validation attempts.</selectable>
              </selectables>
            </title>
          <note role="application">None.</note>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/>
            The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine which authorization factors support validation.
            
            The evaluator shall examine the TSS to review a high-level description if multiple submasks are used within the TOE,
            how the submasks are validated (e.g., each submask validated before combining, once combined validation takes place).
            
            
            <Guidance/>If the validation functionality is configurable, the evaluator shall examine the operational guidance
            to ensure it describes how to configure the TOE to ensure the limits regarding validation attempts can be established. 
            
            <Tests/>The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
            
            Test 1: The evaluator shall determine the limit on the average rate of the number of consecutive failed authorization attempts.
            The evaluator will test the TOE by entering that number of incorrect authorization factors in consecutive attempts to access the
            protected data. If the limit mechanism includes any “lockout” period, the time period tested should include at least one such
            period. Then the evaluator will verify that the TOE behaves as described in the TSS.
            
            Test 2: For each validated authorization factor, ensure that when the user provides an incorrect authorization factor,
            the TOE prevents the decryption of the FEK(s).</aactivity>
            
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        <f-component id="FCS_IV_EXT.1" name="Extended: Initialization Vector Generation">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FCS_IV_EXT.1.1 ">
            <title>The application shall <selectables>
                <selectable>implement platform-provided functionality to generate IVs</selectable>
              <selectable>generate IVs in the following manner
                <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable>CBC: IVs shall be non-repeating and unpredictable;</selectable>
                <selectable>CCM: Nonce shall be non-repeating and unpredictable;</selectable>
                <selectable>XTS: No IV. Tweak values shall be non-negative integers, assigned consecutively,
                  and starting at an arbitrary non-negative integer;</selectable>
                <selectable>GCM: IV shall be non-repeating. The number of invocations of GCM shall not exceed
                  2^32 for a given secret key.</selectable>
              </selectables></selectable>
              </selectables> </title>
            <note role="application">None.</note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/>
              The evaluator shall ensure the TSS describes how nonces are created uniquely and how IVs and tweaks are handled (based on the AES mode).
              The evaluator shall confirm that the nonces are unique and the IVs and tweaks meet the stated requirements.
              
              <Guidance/>None.
              
              <Tests/>None.
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        <f-component id="FCS_KYC_EXT.1" name="Key Chaining and Key Storage">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FCS_KYC_EXT.1.1">
            <title> The TSF shall maintain a key chain of: 
              <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable>a conditioned password as the FEK; </selectable>
                <selectable id="HASKEK">KEKs originating from 
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>one or more authorization factors(s)</selectable>
                    <selectable>a file encryption enterprise management server</selectable>
                  </selectables> to 
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>the FEK(s)</selectable>
                    <selectable>a file encryption enterprise management server</selectable>
                  </selectables>
                  using the following method(s): 
                  <selectables linebreak="yes">
                    <selectable>utilization of the platform key storage</selectable>
                    <selectable>utilization of platform key storage that performs key wrap with a
                      TSF provided key</selectable>
                    <selectable id="USEKEYWRA">implement key wrapping as specified in FCS_COP.1(5)</selectable>
                    <selectable id="USEKEYCOM">implement key combining as specified in FCS_SMC_EXT.1</selectable>
                    <selectable id="USEKEYENC">implement key encryption as specified in FCS_COP.1(7)</selectable>
                    <selectable id="USEKEYTRA">implement key transport as specified in FCS_COP.1(8)</selectable>
                    <selectable id="USEKEYDER">implement key derivation as specified in FCS_KDF_EXT.1</selectable>
                  </selectables> while maintaining an effective strength of 
                    <selectables>
                      <selectable>
                        <selectables>
                          <selectable>128 bits</selectable>
                          <selectable>256 bits</selectable>
                        </selectables> for symmetric keys;
                      </selectable>
                      <selectable>
                        <selectables>
                          <selectable>128 bits</selectable>
                          <selectable>192 bits</selectable>
                          <selectable>256 bits</selectable>
                        </selectables> for asymmetric keys;
                      </selectable>
                    </selectables> commensurate with the strength of the FEK
                </selectable>
              </selectables> 
              and 
              <selectables>
                <selectable> no supplemental key chains</selectable>
                <selectable> other supplemental key chains that protect a key or keys in the primary key chain using the following method(s):
                  <selectables linebreak="yes">
                    <selectable>utilization of the platform key storage</selectable>
                    <selectable>utilization of platform key storage that performs key wrap with a
                      TSF provided key</selectable>
                    <selectable id="USEKEYWRA">implement key wrapping as specified in FCS_COP.1(5)</selectable>
                    <selectable id="USEKEYCOM">implement key combining as specified in FCS_SMC_EXT.1</selectable>
                    <selectable id="USEKEYENC">implement key encryption as specified in FCS_COP.1(7)</selectable>
                    <selectable id="USEKEYTRA">implement key transport as specified in FCS_COP.1(8)</selectable>
                    <selectable id="USEKEYDER">implement key derivation as specified in FCS_KDF_EXT.1</selectable>
                  </selectables></selectable>
              </selectables>
            </title>
            <note role="application">Key Chaining is the method of using multiple layers of
              encryption keys to ultimately secure the FEK. The number of intermediate keys will
              vary. This applies to all keys that contribute to the ultimate wrapping or derivation
              of the FEK. For the first selection, the ST author
              selects the method used for the keychain.  <h:br/>
              
              If the second option is chosen (“KEKs originating…”)
              , then the ST author chooses all methods for production and protection of KEKs in the keychain 
              from the options in the second selection.  For this option, the ST author must also specify the 
              strength of the keys in the keychain.  It should be noted that “maintaining overall strength…
              commensurate with the overall strength of the FEK” is meant to cover the use case for this PP-Module 
              of a powered-off device being recovered by an adversary, who subsequently attempts to recover 
              the FEK through a compromise of the key chain. <h:br/>
              
              The third selection in the requirement is used to select the types of keys used in the key chain 
              (both symmetric and asymmetric keys are allowed).  The bit sizes selected in the fourth 
              and fifth selections are chosen by the ST author to be commensurate with the strength of 
              the FEK in the following manner: for symmetric FEKs of 128 bits, the ST author can select 
              any of the choices for both symmetric and asymmetric keys.  For symmetric FEKs of 256 bits, 
              the ST author selects 256 bits if the symmetric key option is chosen and 192 bits or 256 bits 
              if the asymmetric key option is chosen.<h:br/>
              
              If a supplemental keychain is used, then the ST author selects the second option in the sixth 
              selection and then chooses the method by which these keys are protected.  Keys in the 
              supplemental key chain may be of any size, as they only provide additional protection to the 
              primary key chain.  Compromise (according the PP-Module use case) of the secondary key chain cannot 
              circumvent the protection provided by the primary keychain. <h:br/>
            
             If the selections where the TOE implements KEKs are chosen for the primary or supplimental key chains
              then FCS_CKM_EXT.3 shall be included.<h:br/>
            
            The selections for an enterprise management server permit the key chain may originate or terminate from 
              an enterprise management server.  
            The server may provide a key needed to start a chain or the server may recieve a key that ends a chain.  
              The key mangement internal to the server is not evaluated here. This permits the enterprise management server to 
            function in the middle of a larger key chain.</note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/> or KMD (Key Management Description may be used if necessary details describe proprietary information)
              The evaluator shall verify the TSS contains a high level 
              description of all keychains and authorization methods selected in FIA_AUT_EXT 
              that are used to protect the KEK or FEK. The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes 
              each key chain in detail, and these descriptions correspond with the selections of the requirement. 
              The description of each key chain shall be reviewed to ensure the options for maintaining the key chain are documented.
              
              The evaluator shall verify the TSS to ensure that it describes how each key chain process functions, 
              such that it does not expose any material that might compromise any key in the chain. A high-level 
              description should include a diagram illustrating the keychain(s) implemented and detail where all 
              keys and keying material is stored or how the keys or key material are derived. The evaluator shall examine the primary 
              key chain to ensure that at no point the chain could be broken without a cryptographic exhaust or 
              knowledge of the KEK or FEK and the effective strength of the FEK is maintained throughout the Key Chain 
              as specified in the requirement.
              
              <Guidance/> None. 
              
              <Tests/>None. </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      
      
      
        
              
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="User Data Protection (FDP)" id="fdp">
        <f-component id="FDP_PRT_EXT.1" name="Extended: Protection of Selected User Data">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FDP_PRT_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The TSF shall perform encryption and decryption of the user-selected file (or set
              of files) in accordance with FCS_COP.1(1). </title>
            <note role="application">This is the primary requirement for encrypting and decrypting
              the protected resources (files and sets of files). </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/> FDP_PRT_EXT.1.1: The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine that it
              lists each type of resource that can be encrypted (e.g., file, directory) and what
              “encrypted” means in terms of the resource (e.g., “encrypting a directory” means that
              all of the files contained in the directory are encrypted, but the data in the
              directory itself (which are filenames and pointers to the files) are not encrypted).
              The evaluator shall also confirm that the TSS describes how each type of resource
              listed is encrypted and decrypted by the TOE. The evaluator shall ensure that this
              description includes the case where an existing file or set of files is encrypted for
              the first time; a new file or set of files is created and encrypted; an existing file
              or set of files is re-encrypted (that is, it had been initially encrypted; it was
              decrypted (by the TOE) for use by the user, and is then subsequently re-encrypted);
              and corresponding decryption scenarios. If other scenarios exist due to product
              implementation/features, the evaluator shall ensure that those scenarios are covered
              in the TSS as well. 
              
              <Guidance/> If the TOE creates temporary objects and these
              objects can be protected through administrative measures (e.g., the TOE creates
              temporary files in a designated directory that can be protected through configuration
              of its access control permissions), then the evaluator shall check the Operational
              Guidance to ensure that these measures are described. <h:br/> If there are special
              measures necessary to configure the method by which the file or set of files are
              encrypted (e.g., choice of algorithm used, key size, etc.), then those instructions
              shall be included in the Operational Guidance and verified by the evaluator. In these
              cases, the evaluator checks to ensure that all non-TOE products used to satisfy the
              requirements of the ST that are described in the Operational Guidance are consistent
              with those listed in the ST, and those tested by the evaluation activities of this PP-Module.
                
              <Tests/> The evaluator shall also perform the following tests. All
              instructions for configuring the TOE and each of the environments must be included in
              the Operational Guidance and used to establish the test configuration.<h:br/> For each
              resource and decryption/encryption scenario listed in the TSS, the evaluator shall
              ensure that the TSF is able to successfully encrypt and decrypt the resource using the
              following methodology:<h:br/> Monitor the temporary resources being created (if any) and
              deleted by the TSF—the tools used to perform the monitoring (e.g., procmon for a
              Windows system) shall be identified in the test report. The evaluator shall ensure
              that these resources are consistent with those identified in the TSS, and that they
              are protected as specified in the Operational Guidance and are deleted when the
              decryption/encryption operation is completed. </aactivity>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="FDP_PRT_EXT.1.2">
            <title> The application shall <selectables>
                <selectable>invoke platform-provided functionality</selectable>
                <selectable>implement functionality</selectable>
              </selectables> to ensure that all sensitive data created by the TOE when
              decrypting/encrypting the user-selected file (or set of files) are destroyed in
              volatile and non-volatile memory when the data is no longer needed according to FCS_CKM_EXT4. </title>
            
            <note role="application"> The intent is that the TSF controls the use and clearing of any data
              that it manipulates that is not needed by the user (e.g. a temporary file created in non-volatile
              memory during the encryption/decryption process would be destroyed as soon as the process is completed).
              This should not prevent expected usage (e.g. the TOE may create a decrypted copy of a file as requested
              by the user).The TSF is also not responsible for temporary files that  non-TSF application creates 
              (for example, a text editor may create a “checkpoint” file when editing a file that is protected by the TOE;
              the TOE does not have to try to keep track of or clean up these “checkpoint” files). An optional
              requirement on cleaning up the temporary files created by non-TSF application when operating on
              files protected by the TOE is FDP_PRT_EXT.3.1 
            
            While these data sets are not keys, they can follow the same deletion procedures described in FCS_CKM_EXT.4</note>
            
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/>
              <h:b>Requirement met by the TOE</h:b>
              <h:br/> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure there is a high-level description
              of how the FEK is protected. <h:br/>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure there
              is a description of how the FEK is protected. The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure 
              that it describes all temporary files/resources created or memory used during the 
              decryption/encryption process and when those files/resources or memory is no longer needed. 
              The TSS shall describe how the TSF or TOE platform deletes the non-volatile memory (for example, files) 
              and volatile memory locations after the TSF is done with its decryption/encryption operation. 
              <Guidance/>None. 
              
              <Tests/> 
              <testlist><test>
                This test only applies for application provided functionality.
                
                1. Using a file editor, create and save a text file that is encrypted per the evaluation configured encryption policy.
                The contents of the file will be limited to a known text pattern to ensure that the text pattern will be present in all encryption/decryption operations performed by the TOE.
                
                2. Exit the file editor so that the file (including its known text pattern) has “completed the decryption/encryption operation”
                and process memory containing the known text pattern is released.
                
                3. The evaluator will take a dump of volatile memory and search the generated dump for the known pattern.
                The test fails if the known plaintext pattern is found in the memory dump.
                
                4. Open the file again with a file editor. 
                
                5. The evaluator will take a dump of volatile memory and search the generated dump for the known text pattern.
                Note that the known text pattern is expected to be present since the file editor has the file open.
                The test fails if the known plaintext pattern is not found in the memory dump.
                
                6. Close the file and exit the file editor.
                
                7. The evaluator will take a dump of volatile memory and search the retrieved dump for the known pattern.
                The test fails if the known plaintext pattern is found in the memory dump.
              
                 8. Open the file again with a file editor, edit the contents with a new text pattern, save the file. 
                 
                 9. Exit the file editor so that the file (including its known text pattern) has “completed the decryption/encryption operation”
                 and process memory containing the known text pattern is released.
                 
                 10. The evaluator will take a dump of volatile memory and search the generated dump for the new known pattern.
                 The test fails if the new known plaintext pattern is found in the memory dump.
                 </test></testlist>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="FDP_PRT_EXT.2" name="Extended: Protection of Selected User Data">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FDP_PRT_EXT.2.1">
          <title>The application shall <selectables>
            <selectable>invoke platform-provided functionality</selectable>
            <selectable>implement functionality</selectable>
          </selectables> to ensure that all original plaintext data created when
            decrypting/encrypting the user-selected file (or set of files) are destroyed in volatile
            and non-volatile memory according to FCS_CKM_EXT.4 upon completion of the decryption/encryption operation.
          </title>
          
          <note role="application"> This is the primary requirement for encrypting and decrypting
            the protected resources (file or set of files). <h:br/>
            
            For FDP_PRT_EXT.2.1, the intent is that the TSF controls the use and clearing of any data that it manipulates. It
            needs to ensure that no plaintext data from encrypted resources
            remains after the TSF has finished operating on that resource. In the context of
            FDP_PRT_EXT.2.1, the TSF has completed the decryption operation after it has decrypted
            the file or set of files for use by an application, and completed the encryption
            operation after it has encrypted the file or set of files for storage in the file
            system. 
            
            While these data sets are not keys, they can follow the same deletion procedures described in FCS_CKM_EXT.4
          </note>
          
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/>  The evaluator shall
            examine the TSS to ensure that it describes all temporary file (or set of files) that
            are created in the filesystem of the host during the decryption/encryption process, and
            that the TSS describes how these files are deleted after the TSF is done with its
            decryption/encryption operation. Note that if other objects/resources are created on the
            host that are 1) persistent and 2) visible to other processes (users) on that host that
            are not filesystem objects, those objects shall be identified and described in the TSS
            as well. 
            
            <Guidance/> None. 
            
            <Tests/>
            <testlist>
              <test>For each type of resource that is identified in the TSS as sharable in its
                encrypted form, the evaluator shall ensure that different users using different
                authorization factors are able to successfully access the resource using different
                authorization factors. This should include making changes to the resource to ensure
                that the same resource is being shared, and that a per-user copy of the resource is
                not being made.</test>
              <test>If the TSS creates temporary files/resources
                during file decryption/encryption, the evaluator shall perform the following tests
                to verify that the temporary files/resources are destroyed. The evaluator shall use
                a tool (e.g., procmon for a Windows system) that is capable of monitoring the
                creation and deletion of files during the decryption/encryption process is
                performed. A tool that can search the contents of the hard drive (e.g., winhex) will
                also be needed. The tools used to perform the monitoring shall be identified in the
                test report. </test>
            </testlist> Test 1 (Creating an encrypted document) <h:ul>
              <h:li>Open an editing application.</h:li>
              <h:li>Create a special string inside the document. The string could be 5-10 words. It is
                recommended to remove the spaces. This will create a one page document.</h:li>
              <h:li>Start the file monitoring tool.</h:li>
              <h:li>Save and close the file.</h:li>
              <h:li>Encrypt the file using the TOE (if the TOE does not encrypt automatically for the
                user).</h:li>
            </h:ul>
            <h:b>Analysis Steps </h:b>
            <h:ul>
              <h:li>If needed, exit/close the TOE.</h:li>
              <h:li>Stop the file monitoring tool. View the results. Identify any temporary files that
                were created during the encryption process. Examine to see if the temporary files
                were destroyed when the TOE closed. </h:li>
              <h:li>If temporary files remain, these temporary files should be examined to ensure that
                no plaintext data remains. If plaintext data is found in these files, the test fails.</h:li>
              <h:li>Search the contents of the hard drive (using the second tool) for the plaintext
                string used above. (The search should be performed using both ASCII and Unicode
                formats.)</h:li>
              <h:li>If the string is found, this means that plaintext from the test fails. </h:li>
            </h:ul> Test 2 (Creating, Encrypting a blank document and then adding text): <h:ul>
              <h:li>Encrypt a blank document using the tool.</h:li>
              <h:li>Create a special string inside the document. The string could be 5-10 words. It is
                recommended to remove the spaces. This will create a one page document.</h:li>
              <h:li>Start the file monitoring tool.</h:li>
              <h:li>Save and close the file. </h:li>
              <h:li>Perform the “Analysis Steps” listed above.</h:li>
              
            </h:ul>
            <h:br/>  </aactivity>
        </f-element>
      
      
      </f-component>
      
      
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="Identification and Authentication (FIA)" id="fia">
        <f-component id="FIA_AUT_EXT.1" name="User Authorization">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FIA_AUT_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The application shall 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>implement platform-provided functionality to provide user
                  authorization</selectable>
                <selectable>provide user authorization</selectable>
              </selectables> based on 
              <selectables>
                <selectable id="USEPAS"> a password authorization factor conditioned as defined in FCS_CKM_EXT.1(1)</selectable>
                <selectable id="USECAR">an external Smartcard factor that is at least the same bit-length as the FEK(s), and is protecting a submask that is 
                   <selectables>
                     <selectable>generated by the TOE (using the RBG as specified in FCS_RBG_EXT.1)</selectable>
                     <selectable>generated by the platform</selectable>
                   </selectables> protected using RSA with key size 
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>3072 bits</selectable>
                    <selectable>4096 bits</selectable>
                  </selectables> with user presence proved by presentation of the smartcard and 
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>none</selectable>
                    <selectable>an OE defined PIN</selectable>
                    <selectable>a configurable PIN</selectable>
                  </selectables>
                </selectable>
                <selectable>an external USB token factor that is at least the same security strength as the FEK(s),
                   and is providing a submask generated by the 
                   <selectables>
                     <selectable>TOE (using the RBG as specified in FCS_RBG_EXT.1)</selectable>
                     <selectable>platform</selectable>
                   </selectables>
                </selectable>
              </selectables>
            </title>
            <note role="application"> FCS_RBG_EXT.1 is in the Application Software Protection Profile.
             
             This requirement specifies what authorization factors the TOE accepts
             from the user. A password entered by the user is one authorization factor that the TOE must 
             be able to condition, as specified in FCS_CKM_EXT.1(1). Another option is a smart card
             authorization factor, with the differentiating feature being how the value is generated – either
             by the TOE’s RBG or by the platform. An external USB token may also be used, with the
             submask value generated either by the TOE’s RBG or by the platform.
             The TOE may accept any number of authorization factors, and these are categorized as
             “submasks”. The ST author selects the authorization factors they support, and there may be
             multiple methods for a selection.
             Use of multiple authorization factors is preferable; if more than one authorization factor is
             used, the submasks produced must be combined using FCS_SMC_EXT.1. 
              
            
            </note>
            <aactivity>The evaluation activities for this component will be driven by the selections
              made by the ST author. This section describes evaluation activities for all possible
              selections in an ST; it should be understood that if a capability is not selected in
              the ST, the noted evaluation activity does not need to be performed. 
              
              <TSS/> The
              evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes how user authentication is
              performed. The evaluator shall verify that the authorization methods listed in the TSS
              are specified and included in the requirements in the ST. <h:br/>
              <h:b>Requirement met by the TOE</h:b> <h:br/> The evaluator shall first examine the TSS to ensure that the authorization
              factors specified in the ST are described. For password-based factors the
              examination of the TSS section is performed as part of FCS_CKM_EXT.1(1)
              Evaluation Activities. Additionally in this case, the evaluator shall verify that
              the operational guidance discusses the characteristics of external authorization
              factors (e.g., how the authorization factor must be generated; format(s) or
              standards that the authorization factor must meet) that are able to be used by
              the TOE.
              If other authorization factors are specified, then for each factor, the TSS specifies
              how the factors are input into the TOE.<h:br/>
              <h:b>Requirement met by the platform</h:b><h:br/> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to
              ensure a description is included for how the TOE is invoking the platform
              functionality and how it is getting an authorization value that has appropriate
              entropy. 
              
              <Guidance/>The evaluator shall verify that the AGD guidance includes instructions for all of the
              authorization factors. The AGD will discuss the characteristics of external
              authorization factors (e.g., how the authorization factor is generated; format(s) or
              standards that the authorization factor must meet, configuration of the TPM device
              used) that are able to be used by the TOE.
              
              <Tests/>The evaluator shall ensure that authorization using each selected
              method is tested during the course of the evaluation, setting up the method as
              described in the operational guidance and ensuring that authorization is successful and 
              that failure to provide an authorization factor results in denial to access to plaintext data.
              
              [conditional]: If there is more than one authorization factor, ensure that failure
              to supply a required authorization factor does not result in access to the decrypted
              plaintext data.
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="Security Management (FMT)" id="fmt"> 
        
        
        
        <f-component id="FMT_MEC_EXT.1" name="Supported Configuration Mechanism">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FMT_MEC_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The TSF shall 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>invoke the mechanisms recommended by the platform vendor for storing and setting configuration options</selectable>
                <selectable>store and protect configuration options as specified in FCS_COP.1(1)</selectable>  
              </selectables>.
            </title>
            <note role="application"> The ST author replaces FMT_MEC_EXT.1 in the Application Software PP with this requirement, 
              and performs the appropriate selections.  The ST author ensures all configuration options are "covered" by one of 
              the two selections.  It is allowable to have some configuration stored and protected using platform-provided functions 
              and some stored by the TSF and protected using encryption per FCS_COP.1(1).
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/>The TSS evaluation activity in the Application Software PP for FMT_MEC_EXT.1 applies for either selection.  
              Additionally, if "store and protect configuration options as specified in FCS_COP.1(1)" is selected, the evaluator 
              shall ensure that the TSS identifies those options, as well as indicates where the encrypted representation of these options is stored.
              
              The test evaluation activites in the Application Software PP for FMT_MEC_EXT.1 apply to all configuration options 
              identified as being stored and set using platform mechanisms.  The following test activity applies to any configuration 
              options identified as being stored and protected using encryption per FCS_COP.1(1).
              
              [Conditional] For all configuration options listed in the TSS as being stored and protected using encryption 
              per FCS_COP.1(1), the evaluator shall examine the contents of the configuration option storage (identified in the TSS) to 
              determine that the options have been encrypted. 
            <Guidance/> None.
              <Tests/> None.
              
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="Protection of the TSF (FPT)" id="fpt">
        
      
        <f-component id="FPT_KYP_EXT.1" name="Extended: Protection of Key and Key Material (FPT_KYP_EXT)">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FPT_KYP_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The TSF shall 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>not store keys in non-volatile memory</selectable>
                <selectable>only store keys in non-volatile memory when
                  <selectables linebreak="yes">
                    <selectable>wrapped, as specified in FCS_COP.1(5)</selectable>
                    <selectable>encrypted, as specified in FCS_COP.1(7)</selectable>
                    <selectable>the plaintext key is stored in the underlying platform's keystore as specified by FCS_STO_EXT.1.1</selectable>
                    <selectable>the plaintext key is not part of the key chain as specified in FCS_KYC_EXT.1.</selectable>
                    <selectable>the plaintext key will no longer provide access to the encrypted data after initial provisioning</selectable>
                    <selectable>the plaintext key is a key split that is combined as specified in FCS_SMC_EXT.1 and another contribution to the split is
                     <selectables linebreak="yes">
                       <selectable>wrapped as specified in FCS_COP.1(5)</selectable>
                       <selectable>encrypted as specified in FCS_COP.1(7)</selectable>
                       <selectable>derived as specified in FCS_KDF_EXT.1.1 and not stored in non-volatile memory</selectable>
                       <selectable>supplied by the enterprise management server</selectable>
                     </selectables>
                    </selectable>
                    <selectable>the plaintext key is stored on an external storage device for use as an authorization factor.</selectable>
                    <selectable>the plaintext key is used to encrypt a key as specified in FCS_COP.1(7) or wrap a key as specified in FCS_COP.1(5) 
                      that is already encrypted as specified in FCS_COP.1(7) or wrapped as specified in FCS_COP.1(5)</selectable>
                  </selectables>
                </selectable>
                </selectables>
            </title>
            <note role="application">The plaintext key storage in non-volatile memory is allowed for
              several reasons. If the keys exist within protected memory that is not user accessible
              on the TOE or OE, the only methods that allow it to play a security relevant role for
              protecting the FEK is if it is a key split or providing additional layers of wrapping
              or encryption on keys that have already been protected. </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/> or KMD (Key Management Description may be used if necessary details describe proprietary information)
              
              The evaluator shall verify the TSS for a high level description of the method(s) used
              to protect keys stored in non-volatile memory.<h:br/> The evaluator shall verify
              the TSS to ensure it describes the storage location of all keys and the protection of
              all keys stored in non-volatile memory. The description of the key chain shall be
              reviewed to ensure FCS_COP.1(5) is followed for the storage of wrapped or encrypted
              keys in non-volatile memory and plaintext keys in non-volatile memory meet one of the
              criteria for storage. 
              
              <Guidance/> None. 
              
              <Tests/> None. </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection></man-sfrs>
    <opt-sfrs>
        <f-component id="FIA_FCT_EXT.1" name="Extended: Multi-User Authorization">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FIA_FCT_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The TSF shall support the use of authorization factors from multiple users that result in unique KEKs.</title></f-element>
          
          <f-element id="FIA_FCT_EXT.1.2">
            <title>The TSF shall support
            <selectables>
              <selectable>Authorized User Key sharing via key transport as specified in FCS_COP.1.1(8)</selectable>
              <selectable>Distribution of a shared key from an enterprise management Server</selectable>
            </selectables>
            </title>
          
         
            <note role="application"> While FIA_FCT_EXT.1.1 requires the TSF to support multiple
              authorization factors to produce multiple KEKs, the intent is that the TSF supports a
              system where multiple users have access to files on the underlying platform, and that
              each user has an authorization factor so that they can protect their own files from
              other users. This should be accomplished via the methods detailed in FIA_FCT_EXT.1.2 
               </note>
          
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/>  
              The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine that it
              identifies each of the resources that is sharable in encrypted form (for instance,
              encrypted files may be sharable among users, but encrypted directories may not), and the
              method by which the resource can be shared among users with different authorization
              factors. <h:br/>
              
              The evaluator shall examine the operation
              guidance to determine that it contains instructions on how to set up and share resources
              with other users, if additional actions are necessary due to use of the encryption
              product. If different for different underlying platforms, the evaluator determines that
              all platforms listed in the ST are addressed.
              
              <Guidance/> - The evaluator shall examine the operation guidance to
              determine that it contains instructions on how to set up and share resources
              with other users, if additional actions are necessary due to use of the
              encryption product. If different for different underlying platforms, the
              evaluator determines that all platforms listed in the ST are addressed.
              
              <Tests/> 
              Test 1: For each type of resource that is identified in the TSS as sharable in its
              encrypted form, the evaluator shall ensure that different users using different
              authorization factors are able to successfully access the resource using
              different authorization factors. This should include making changes to the
              resource to ensure that the same resource is being shared, and that a per-user
              copy of the resource is not being made.
              
              Test 2: For each type of resource that is identified in the TSS as sharable in its
              encrypted form, the evaluator shall ensure that a different unauthorized user is unable to access the encrypted file shared.
              This test succeeds if the unauthorized user is unable to access a file shared between other authoirzed users.
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component name="Extended: Protection of Third Party Data" id="FDP_PRT_EXT.3">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FDP_PRT_EXT.3.1">
          <title>The TSF shall ensure that all temporary files created by 
            <selectables>
              <selectable>all applications</selectable>
              <selectable><assignable>subset of applications that can integrate with the FE</assignable></selectable>
            </selectables>when decrypting/encrypting the
            user-selected file (or set of files) are removed or encrypted upon completion of the
            decryption/encryption operation.</title>
       
          <note role="application"> This requirement is to cover the detection and encryption of temporary files created by third party applications.
            If the FE provides a capability to allow specific applications to leverage it, the applications or method they would use to opt in may be included in the assignement.  
          </note>
          
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/>  The evaluator shall
            examine the TSS to ensure that it describes how the TOE detects and encrypts temporary files (or set of files) that
            are created in the filesystem of the host by third party products,
            
            <Guidance/> [conditional]  If any configuration is required for this process the evaluator shall verify it is described in the guidence documentation. 
            
            <Tests/>The evaluator shall utilize any third party application that would be protected under this protection to generate files, then verify those files are being encrypted.</aactivity>
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
        <f-component id="FDP_PM_EXT.1" name="Extended: Protection of  Data in Power Managed States">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FDP_PM_EXT.1.1">
          <title>The TSF shall protect all data selected for encryption during the transition to
            the <assignable>powered-down state(s) or locked system states for which this capability is provided</assignable> state as
            per FDP_PRT_EXT.1.1.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_PM_EXT.1.2">
          <title>On the return to a powered-on state from the state(s) indicated in FDP_PM_EXT.1.1,
            the TSF shall authorize the user in the manner specified in FIA_AUT_EXT.1.1 once before
            any protected data are decrypted. </title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_PM_EXT.1.3">
          <title>The TSF shall destroy all key material and authentication factors stored in plaintext when transitioning to a
           protected state as defined by FDP_PM_EXT.1.1.</title>
        <note role="application"> For the first assignment, the ST author fills in the state(s) using
            the same name used in the Operational Guidance for the state that is appropriately
            protected by the TOE. <h:br/> It should be noted that it is not sufficient to use
            Operational Environment-based credentials to unlock the TOE from the indicated state;
            the intent is that returning from the indicated state is equivalent (from an
            authorization point of view) to returning from a completely powered-off state and
            re-opening the resources that are protected. </note>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/>The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes the state(s)
            that are supported by this capability. For each state, the evaluator ensures that the
            TSS contains a description of how the state is entered, and the actions of the TSF on
            entering the state, specifically addressing how multiple open resources (of each type)
            are protected, and how keying material associated with these resources is protected (if
            different from that described elsewhere). The TSF shall also describe how the state is
            exited, and how the requirements are met during this transition to an operational state.
            
            The evaluator shall verify the TSS provides a description of what keys and key material are destroyed when entering any protected state.
            
            <h:h4>KMD</h:h4> The evaluator shall verify the KMD includes a description of the areas where keys and key material reside.
              The evaluator shall verify the KMD includes a key lifecycle that includes a description where key material reside,
              how the key material is used, and how the material is destroyed once a claimed power state is entered
              and that the documentation in the KMD follows FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1 for the destruction.
              
            <Guidance/> The evaluator shall check the Operational Guidance to determine that
            it describes the states that are supported by the TOE, and provides information related
            to the correct configuration of these modes and the TOE. 
            
            The evaluator shall validate that guidance documentation contains clear warnings and information on conditions in which the TOE
            may end up in a non-protected state. In that case it must contain mitigation instructions on what to do in such scenarios.
            
            <Tests/> The following
            tests must be performed by the evaluator for each supported State, type of resource,
            platform, and authorization factor:<testlist>
              <test>Following the Operational guidance, configure the Operational Environment and
                the TOE so that the lower power state of the platform is enabled and protected by the TOE. Open several
                resources (documented in the test report) that are protected. Invoke the lower power
                state. On resumption of normal power attempt to access a previously-opened
                protected resource, observe that an incorrect entry of the authorization factor(s)
                does not result in access to the system, and that correct entry of the authorization
                factor(s) does result in access to the resources. </test>
            </testlist>
          </aactivity>
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
        <f-component id="FDP_AUT_EXT.1" name="Extended: Authentication of Selected User Data">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.1.1">
          <title>The TSF shall perform authentication of the user-selected file (or set of files)
            and provide notification to the user if modification had been detected. </title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.1.2">
          <title> The TSF shall implement a data authentication method based on <selectables>
              <selectable>cryptographic keyed hashing service and verification in accordance with
                FDP_AUT_EXT.2</selectable>
              <selectable>asymmetric signing and verification in accordance with
                FDP_AUT_EXT.3</selectable>
            </selectables>. </title>
          <note role="application">This is the primary requirement for authentication of the
            protected resources (files and sets of files). It is highly encouraged for vendors to
            utilize a keyed hashing service or asymmetric signing mechanism to ensure data
            authentication, as these are the only two implementations noted in this PP-Module that prevent
            decryption if authentication is unsuccessful. Using modes such as XTS or CBC will
            require additional data authentication measures to be added, such as a keyed hash
            function or asymmetric signing, because these modes do not come inherently packaged with
            data authentication or a way to signal to the user that data has been modified.<h:br/>
          
            Specific tests are performed in FDP_AUT_EXT.2 or FDP_AUT_EXT.3 depending on the selection made in FDP_AUT_EXT.1.2.
          </note>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine that it lists each type of
            resource that can be authenticated (e.g., file, directory) and what “authenticated”
            means in terms of the resource (e.g., “authenticating a directory” means that all of the
            files contained in the directory are authenticated, but the data in the directory itself
            (which are filenames and pointers to the files) are not authenticated). The evaluator
            shall also confirm that the TSS describes how each type of resource listed is
            authenticated by the TOE and how authentication measures are added to each resource
            (e.g. taking all the encrypted files through a MAC function and appending the MAC to the
            set of files). The evaluator shall ensure that this description includes the case where
            an existing file or set of files has authentication measures added for the first time; a
            new file or set of files is created and adds authentication measure; an existing file or
            set of files updates or replaces its existing authentication measures (that is, it had a
            MAC appended to the data; it was authenticated and decrypted (by the TOE) for use by the
            user, and is then subsequently re-encrypted with an updated MAC); and corresponding
            decryption scenarios. If other scenarios exist due to product implementation/features,
            the evaluator shall ensure that those scenarios are covered in the TSS as well.
              
            <Guidance/>If the TOE creates temporary objects and these objects can be
            protected through administrative measures (e.g., the TOE creates temporary files in a
            designated directory that can be protected through configuration of its access control
            permissions), then the evaluator shall check the Operational Guidance to ensure that
            these measures are described. <h:br/>If there are special measures necessary to configure
            the method by which the file or set of files are authenticated (e.g., choice of function
            used, additional keys, etc.), then those instructions shall be included in the
            Operational Guidance and verified by the evaluator. This includes, for instance, lists
            of allowed platforms, libraries, and devices, and instructions for using them. In these
            cases, the evaluator checks to ensure that all non-TOE products used to satisfy the
            requirements of the ST that are described in the Operational Guidance are consistent
            with those listed in the ST, and those tested by the evaluation activities of this PP-Module.
            
            <Tests/>The evaluator shall also perform the following tests.
            These tests must be performed for each data authentication feature and
            platform claimed in the ST; all instructions for configuring the TOE and each of the
            environments must be included in the Operational Guidance and used to establish the test
            configuration. <h:br/>For each resource and data authentication scenario listed in the
            TSS, the evaluator shall ensure that the TSF is able to successfully add authentication
            measures and authenticate the resource using the following methodology. <h:br/>Monitor the
            temporary resources being created (if any) and deleted by the TSF—the tools used to
            perform the monitoring (e.g., procmon for a Windows system) shall be identified in the
            test report. The evaluator shall ensure that these resources are consistent with those
            identified in the TSS, and that they are protected as specified in the Operational
            Guidance and are deleted when the decryption/encryption and authentication operations
            are completed. </aactivity>
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
      <f-component id="FDP_AUT_EXT.2" name="Extended: Data Authentication using cryptographic, keyed hash functions">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.2.1">
          <title>The TSF shall use a cryptographic, keyed hash function in accordance with
            FCS_COP.1(4).</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.2.2">
          <title>The TSF shall use a File Authentication Key (FAK) in accordance with FCS_COP_EXT.1(6)
            and FCS_CKM_EXT.5 as the secret key to the keyed hash function.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.2.3">
          <title>The TSF shall use the entirety of the ciphertext file as the message input to the
            keyed hash function.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.2.4">
          <title>The TSF shall concatenate the output of the keyed hash function, the Message
            Authentication Code (MAC).</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.2.5">
          <title>The TSF shall authenticate the encrypted file prior to decryption.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.2.6">
          <title>The TSF shall authenticate the data by comparing the keyed hash output of the
            ciphertext against the stored MAC.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.2.7">
          <title>The TSF shall notify the user of an unsuccessful authentication and prevent
            decryption of the ciphertext.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.2.8">
          <title>During verification, the TSF shall verify the MAC is at the end of the ciphertext
            file.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.2.9">
          <title>The FAK will be generated using a RBG that meets FCS_RBG_EXT.1 (from the AS
            PP).</title>
          <note role="application">The intent of this requirement is to specify the correct way of
            using a keyed hash function to authenticate the data, and enable authentication of data. 
          FAKs are considered cryptographic keys and are subject to destruction per FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1</note>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/> The evaluator shall check the TSS section to confirm that it describes
            how a request for each type of supported resource (file (or set of files)) will result
            in data authentication using a keyed hash function. The evaluator will confirm that the
            TOE will respond appropriately to a failed authentication, to include notifying the user
            of an invalid authentication and preventing decryption. The evaluator will confirm that
            any file encryption utility will be able to identify where the MAC is placed. <h:br/>The
            evaluator will confirm that a FAK is used as part of the authentication process and will
            identify the keyed hash function utilized. 
            
            <Guidance/> It is encouraged for
            every implementation to use a FAK that is wholly different and independently generated
            from the FEK. 
            
            <Tests/> The evaluator shall perform the following test: <testlist>
              <test>Create an encrypted file and confirm that authentication of this file using the
                correct FAK will result in a successful decryption.</test>
              <test>Modify an arbitrary number of bits of ciphertext and attempt to run the
                authentication and decryption operations on the file. Assert that the TOE
                successfully identified the forged ciphertext file and notified the user. </test>
            </testlist>
          </aactivity>
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
        
      <f-component id="FDP_AUT_EXT.3" name="Extended: Data Authentication using asymmetric signing and verification">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.3.1">
          <title>The TSF shall use a secure hash function in accordance with FCS_COP.1(2) (from the
              <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>) with the entire ciphertext file as input to create a
            hash.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.3.2">
          <title>The TSF shall use a cryptographic signing function in accordance with FCS_COP.1(3)
            (from the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>) and must use the hash generated in accordance with
            FDP_AUT_EXT.3.1 as input to the signing process. Additionally, use of ephemeral key for
            signing purposes is prohibited.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.3.3">
          <title>The TSF shall use a public and private key pair generated in accordance with
            FIA_CKM.1(1) and must use this key pair as part of the cryptographic signing process in
            accordance with FDP_AUT_EXT.3.2.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.3.4">
          <title>The TSF shall authenticate the ciphertext data prior to decryption.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.3.5">
          <title>The TSF shall notify the user of an unsuccessful authentication and prevent
            decryption of the ciphertext if such an event were to occur.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.3.6">
          <title>The TSF shall append the signature to the end of the ciphertext file.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FDP_AUT_EXT.3.7">
          <title>During verification, the TSF shall verify the signature is at the end of the
            ciphertext file.</title>
          <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to specify the secure way of
            using a cryptographic signing and hashing function as part of the data authentication
            mechanism.</note>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/> The evaluator shall check the TSS section to confirm that it describes
            how a request for each type of supported resource (file (or set of files)) will result
            in data authentication using a secure hash and cryptographic signing process. The
            evaluator will confirm that the supplied public and private key pair were generated in
            accordance with FCS_CKM.1(1). The evaluator will confirm that the entire ciphertext file
            was used to create the hash and that the hash was used as input to the cryptographic
            signing function. The evaluator will confirm that the TSF notifies the user of an
            unsuccessful authentication and prevents decryption.  The evaluator shall confirm
            that the signature is appended to the end of the ciphertext file.
            
            <Guidance/> None.
              <Tests/>The evaluator shall perform the following test: <testlist>
              <test>Create an encrypted file and demonstrate that authentication of this file using
                the correct keying material will be successful.</test>
              <test>Modify an arbitrary number of bits of ciphertext and attempt to run the
                authentication and decryption operations on the file. Assert that the TOE
                successfully identified the forged ciphertext file and notified the user. </test>
            </testlist>
          </aactivity>
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
          
      <f-component id="FCS_COP_EXT.1(6)" name="FAK encryption/decryption support">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FCS_COP_EXT.1.1(6)">
          <title>The FAK shall be protected in the same manner as the FEK, in accordance with
            FCS_COP.1(5).</title>
          <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to clarify that, if a FAK is
            to be used, it should be treated as sensitive as the FEK, and thus, follow the same
            encryption and decryption practices. </note>
          <aactivity> 
            <TSS/>The evaluator shall follow the evaluation activities as laid out in
            FCS_COP.1(5) to assert proper FAK protection. </aactivity>
          
          
        </f-element>
      
      </f-component>
        <f-component id="FCS_CKM_EXT.5" name="File Authentication Key (FAK) Support">
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.5.1">
          <title> The TSF shall use a FAK to authenticate sensitive data when a cryptographic, keyed
            hashing function is used for data authentication and shall be supported in the following
            manner: <selectables linebreak="yes">
              <selectable>A FAK conditioned from a password/passphrase shall never be stored in
                non-volatile memory</selectable>
              <selectable>a FAK will be stored in non-volatile memory encrypted with a KEK as
                specified in FCS_COP.1(5) using authorization factors as specified in FIA_AUT_EXT.1
              </selectable>
            </selectables>
          </title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.5.2">
          <title>The TSF shall create a unique FAK for each file (or set of files) using the
            mechanism on the client as specified in FCS_RBG_EXT.1.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.5.3">
          <title>The FAKs must be generated by the TOE as specified in FDP_AUT_EXT.2.9.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.5.4">
          <title>The TSF will not write FAKs to non-volatile memory.</title>
        </f-element>
        <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.5.5">
          <title>The FAK shall be protected in a manner conformant to FCS_COP_EXT.1(6).</title>
          <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to describe the different
            methods that a FAK can be created and formed. <h:br/>FCS_CKM_EXT.5.1 details how a FAK mis stored. <h:br/>FCS_CKM_EXT.5.2 requires that each resource to be encrypted
            has a unique FAK, and that this FAK is generated by the TSF. If the encrypted resource
            is a set of files encrypted under one FAK, additional requirements on the initialization
            vectors and cipher modes must be adhered to in Section 4.2. </note>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/> FCS_CKM_EXT.5.1: The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine how the FAK is stored (or not stored) in memory.
            <h:br/> FCS_CKM_EXT.5.2: The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine that it
            describes how a FAK is created for a protected resource and associated with that
            resource; protection of the FAK itself is covered by FCS_COP.1(5). The evaluator
            confirms that—per this description—the FAK is unique per resource (file or set of files)
            and that the FAK is created using the mechanisms specified in FCS_CKM_EXT.1. <h:br/>
            FCS_CKM_EXT.5.3: The TSS must detail that the FAKs are generated on the client machine
            and are not generated on an external server. <h:br/> FCS_CKM_EXT.5.4: FCS_CKM_EXT.4
            contains the requirements necessary to ensure that plaintext keys and key material do
            not remain in plaintext form in the TSF’s non-volatile memory space. In TOEs where the
            FAK is protected with a KEK, the FAK will need to be encrypted and stored in
            non-volatile memory when not being used to decrypt/encrypt a file. (Typically, the
            encrypted FAK is stored in the meta-data of the encrypted file(s).) The evaluator shall
            examine the TSS to ensure that it describes how the FAK is encrypted, both after its
            initial creation and after it has been decrypted for use (note that in the entirely
            likely possibility that the FAK is not re-encrypted, then this case must be indicated in
            the TSS and the description for FCS_CKM_EXT.4 will cover disposal of the plaintext FEK
            and FAK). The evaluator shall further check to ensure that the TSS describes how the FAK
            and any other associated meta-data necessary to decrypt the file or set of files are
            associated with the resource. This description can be combined with the description
            required for FCS_COP.1(5). <h:br/>
            
            <Guidance/> None. 
            
            <Tests/> An example ciphertext file generated via the TOE
            shall be provided to the evaluator with the accompanying FAK and prerequisite
            authorization information used for encryption. The evaluator will use the TOE in
            conjunction with a debugging or forensics utility to attempt an authentication of the
            ciphertext file using the provided authorization information. The evaluator will then
            terminate processing of the TOE and perform a search through non-volatile memory using
            the provided FAK string. The evaluator must document each command, program or action
            taken during this process, and must confirm that the FAK was never written to
            non-volatile memory. This test must be performed three times to ensure repeatability. If
            during the course of this testing the evaluator finds that the FAK was written to
            non-volatile memory, they should be able to identify the cause (i.e. the TOE wrote the
            FAK to disk, the TOE platform dumped volatile memory as a page file, etc), and document
            the reason for failure to comply with the requirement. </aactivity>
        </f-element>
      </f-component></opt-sfrs>
    
    
    <sel-sfrs>
      <f-component id="FCS_CKM_EXT.3" name="Key Encrypting Key (KEK) Support">
        <selection-depends req="FCS_KYC_EXT.1.1"  ids="HASKEK"/>
        <consistency-rationale>
        </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.3.1 ">
          <title> The TSF shall 
            <selectables>
              <selectable>accept KEK from an enterprise management server</selectable>
              <selectable> generate KEK cryptographic keys <h:br/>
                <selectables linebreak="yes">
                  <selectable> using a Random Bit Generator as specified in FCS_RBG_EXT.1 (from the AS
                    PP) and with entropy corresponding to the security strength of AES key sizes of
                    <selectables>
                      <selectable>128 bit</selectable>
                      <selectable>256 bit</selectable>
                    </selectables></selectable>
                  <selectable> derived from a password/passphrase that is conditioned as defined in FCS_CKM_EXT.1(1) </selectable>
                </selectables>
              </selectable>
            </selectables>
          </title>
          <note role="Application">This requirement shall be included in STs in which KEKs originating from is chosen in FCS_KYC_EXT.1.1. </note>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/>
            The evaluator shall review the TSS to determine that a
            description covering how and when KEK(s) are generated exists. The description must
            cover all environments on which the TOE is claiming conformance, and include any
            preconditions that must exist in order to successfully generate the KEKs. The evaluator shall verify 
            that the description of how the KEK(s) are generated is consistent with
            the instructions in the AGD guidance, and any differences that arise from different
            platforms are taken into account. <h:br/> <h:br/> 
            
            Conditional: <h:br/> 
            If using a RBG was selected the evaluator shall examine the TSS and verify that it describes how the functionality
            described by FCS_RBG_EXT.1 (from the <cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>) is invoked to
            generate KEK(s). To the extent possible from the description of the RBG functionality in
            FCS_RBG_EXT.1 (from the App PP), the evaluator shall determine that the key size being
            requested is identical to the key size selected.  <h:br/> <h:br/> 
            
            Conditional: <h:br/>               
            If derived from a password/passphrase is selected the examination of the TSS section is performed as
            part of FCS_CKM_EXT.1(1) evaluation activities. <h:br/>  <h:br/> 
            
            <Guidance/> The evaluator shall review the
            instructions in the AGD guidance to determine that any explicit actions that need to
            be taken by the user to establish a KEK exist—taking into account any differences that
            arise from different platforms—and are consistent with the description in the TSS.
            
            <Tests/> None. 
          </aactivity>
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
      <f-component id="FCS_SMC_EXT.1" name="Submask Combining">
        <selection-depends req="FCS_KYC_EXT.1.1"  ids="USEKEYCOM"/>
        <consistency-rationale>
        </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FCS_SMC_EXT.1.1 ">
          <title>The TSF shall combine submasks using the following method <selectables>
              <selectable>exclusive OR (XOR)</selectable>
              <selectable>SHA-256</selectable>
              <selectable>SHA-384</selectable>
              <selectable>SHA-512</selectable>
            <selectable>HMAC-SHA-256</selectable>
            <selectable>HMAC-SHA-384</selectable>
            <selectable>HMAC-SHA-512</selectable>
            </selectables> to generate an intermediary key</title>
          <note role="application">This requirement specifies the way that a product may combine the
            various submasks by using either an XOR or an approved SHA-hash. This requirement is selection dependent on FCS_KYC_EXT.1.1.</note>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/> If keys are XORed together to form an intermediate key, the TSS section
            shall identify how this is performed (e.g., if there are ordering requirements, checks
            performed, etc.). The evaluator shall also confirm that the TSS describes how the length
            of the output produced is at least the same as that of the FEK. 
            
            <Guidance/>None.
            <Tests/>None.
          </aactivity>
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
        <f-component id="FCS_CKM_EXT.1(1)" name="Extended: Cryptographic key generation (Password/Passphrase conditioning)"> 
          <selection-depends req="FIA_AUT_EXT.1.1" ids="USEPAS"/>
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
        <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.1.1(1)">
          <title>
            The TSF shall support a password/passphrase of up to 
            [assignment: maximum password size, positive integer of 64 or more] 
            characters used to generate a password authorization factor.
           </title>
        </f-element>
          <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.1.2(1)">
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow passwords to be composed of any combination of upper case characters,
              lower case characters, numbers, and the following special characters: “!”, “@”, “#”, “$”, “%”, “^”, “&amp;”, “*”, “(“, and “)”,
              and <selectables>
                <selectable><assignable>other supported special characters</assignable></selectable>
                <selectable>no other characters</selectable>
              </selectables></title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.1.3(1)">
            <title>
              The TSF shall perform [Password-based Key Derivation
              Functions] in accordance with a specified cryptographic algorithm [HMAC- <selectables>
                <selectable>SHA-256</selectable>
                <selectable>SHA-384</selectable>
                <selectable>SHA-512</selectable>
              </selectables> ], with [assignment: positive integer of 4096 or more] iterations, and
              output cryptographic key sizes <selectables>
                <selectable>128</selectable>
                <selectable>256</selectable>
              </selectables> that meet the following: [NIST SP 800-132]. 
              </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.1.4(1)">
            <title>
              The TSF shall not accept passwords less than 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>a value settable by the administrator</selectable>
                <selectable><assignable>minimum password length accepted by the TOE, must be >= 1 </assignable></selectable>
              </selectables> and greater than the maximum password length 
              defined in FCS_CKM_EXT.1.1(1).</title>
          </f-element>
        <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.1.5(1)">
          <title>The TSF shall generate all salts using a RBG that meets FCS_RBG_EXT.1 (from the App PP) and with entropy 
            corresponding to the security strength selected for PBKDF in FCS_CKM_EXT.1.3(1).</title>
          <note role="application"> The password/passphrase is represented on the host machine as a sequence of characters whose 
            encoding depends on the TOE and the underlying OS. This sequence must be conditioned into a string of bits that is to be used as a KEK that is the same size as the FEK.
            
            For FCS_CKM_EXT.1.1(1), the ST author assigns the maximum size of the password/passphrase it supports; it must support at least 64 characters.
            
            For FCS_CKM_EXT.1.2(1), the ST author assigns any other supported characters; if there are no other supported characters, 
            they should select “no other characters”.
            
            For FCS_CKM_EXT.1.3(1), the ST author selects the parameters based on the PBKDF used by the TSF. The key cryptographic
            key sizes in FCS_CKM_EXT.1.3(1) are made to correspond to the KEK key sizes selected in FCS_CKM_EXT.1.
            
            The password/passphrase must be conditioned into a string of bits that forms the submask to be used as input into the
            KEK. Conditioning is performed using one of the identified hash functions in accordance with the process described in
            NIST SP 800-132. SP 800-132 requires the use of a pseudo-random function (PRF) consisting of HMAC with an approved hash function.
            
            Appendix A of SP 800-132 recommends setting the iteration count in order to increase the computation needed to derive
            a key from a password and, therefore, increase the workload of performing a password recovery attack. However, for this PP-Module,
            a minimum iteration count of 4096 is required in order to ensure that twelve bits of security is added to the password/passphrase value.
            A significantly higher value is recommended to ensure optimal security.
            
            For FCS_CKM_EXT.1.4(1) If the minimum password length is settable, then ST author chooses “a value settable by the administrator
            for this component, as well as the “configure password/passphrase complexity setting” item for FMT_SMF.2. If the minimum length
            is not settable, the ST author fills in the assignment with the minimum length the password must be (zero-length passwords are not allowed for compliant TOEs).  
            
            This requirement is selection dependent on FIA_AUT_EXT.1.1.</note>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS/> FCS_CKM_EXT.1.1(1): There are two aspects of this component that require
            evaluation: passwords/passphrases of the length specified in the requirement (at least
            64 characters) are supported, and that the characters that are input are subject to the
            selected conditioning function. These activities are separately addressed in the text
            below. 
            
            <h:br/>Support for minimum length:The evaluators shall check to ensure that the 
            TSS describes the allowable ranges for password/passphrase lengths, and that at least 64 characters may be specified by the user.
            
            <h:br/>Support for character set: The evaluator shall check to ensure that the 
            TSS describes the allowable character set and that it contains the characters listed in the SFR.
            
            <h:br/>Support for PBKDF: The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure
            that the formation of all KEKs or FEKs (as decided in the FCS_CKM_EXT.3 selection) is
            described and that the key sizes match that described by the ST author. 
            
            <h:br/>The
            evaluator shall check that the TSS describes the method by which the password/passphrase
            is first encoded and then fed to the SHA algorithm. The settings for the algorithm
            (padding, blocking, etc.) shall be described, and the evaluator shall verify that these
            are supported by the selections in this component as well as the selections concerning
            the hash function itself. The evaluator shall verify that the TSS contains a description
            of how the output of the hash function is used to form the submask that will be input
            into the function and is the same length as the KEK as specified in FCS_CKM_EXT.4.
            
            <h:br/>For the NIST SP 800-132-based conditioning of the password/passphrase, the required
            evaluation activities will be performed when doing the evaluation activities for the
            appropriate requirements (FCS_COP.1.1(4)). If any manipulation of the key is performed
            in forming the submask that will be used to form the FEK or KEK, that process shall be
            described in the TSS. 
            
            <h:br/>No explicit testing of the formation of the submask from the
            input password is required. 
            
            <h:br/> FCS_CKM_EXT.1.2(1): The ST author shall provide a
            description in the TSS regarding the salt generation. The evaluator shall confirm that
            the salt is generated using an RBG described in FCS_RBG_EXT.1 (from the <cite
              linkend="bibAppPP"/>). <h:h4>Guidance</h:h4>
            
            <h:b>Support for minimum length:</h:b> The evaluators shall check the Operational Guidance 
            to determine that there are instructions on how to generate large passwords/passphrases, and
            instructions on how to configure the password/passphrase length (and optional complexity settings)
            to provide entropy commensurate with the keys that the authorization factor is protecting.  
            
            <Guidance/> None.
            
            <Tests/> Support for Password/Passphrase characteristics: In addition to the analysis above, 
            the evaluator shall also perform the following tests on a TOE configured according to the Operational Guidance: <testlist>
              <test>Ensure that the TOE supports passwords/passphrases of a minimum length of 64 characters. </test>
              <test>Ensure that the TOE does not accept more than the maximum number of characters specified in FCS_CKM_EXT.1.1(1). </test>
              <test> Ensure that the TOE does not accept less than the minimum number of characters specified in FCS_CKM_EXT.1.4(1).
                If the minimum length is settable by the administrator, the evaluator determines the minimum length or lengths to test.</test>
              <test> Ensure that the TOE supports passwords consisting of all characters listed in FCS_CKM_EXT.1.2(1).</test>
            </testlist>
            <h:b>Conditioning:</h:b> No explicit testing of the formation of the authorization factor
            from the input password/passphrase is required. </aactivity>
        </f-element>
      </f-component>
        <f-component id="FCS_COP.1(8)" name="Cryptographic operation (Key Transport)">
          <selection-depends req="FCS_KYC_EXT.1.1" ids="USEKEYTRA"/>
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FCS_COP.1.1(8)">
            <title>
              The TSF shall perform [key transport] in accordance with a
              specified cryptographic algorithm [RSA] in the following modes 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>KTS-OAEP</selectable>
                <selectable>KTS-KEM-KWS</selectable>
              </selectables> and the cryptographic key size of 3072 bits that meet the following: [NIST SP 800-56B, Revision 1].
            </title>
            <note role="application"> This requirement is used in the body of the ST if the ST author chooses to
              use key transport in the key chaining approach that is specified in FCS_KYC_EXT.1.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/>
              The evaluator shall verify the TSS provides a high level description of the RSA
                scheme and the cryptographic key size that is being used, and that the asymmetric
                algorithm being used for key transport is RSA. If more than one scheme/key size are
                allowed, then the evaluator shall make sure and test all combinations of scheme and
                key size. There may be more than one key size to specify – an RSA modulus size
                (and/or encryption exponent size), an AES key size, hash sizes, MAC key/MAC tag
                size.
                If the KTS-OAEP scheme was selected, the evaluator shall verify that the TSS
                identifies the hash function, the mask generating function, the random bit generator,
                the encryption primitive and decryption primitive.
                If the KTS-KEM-KWS scheme was selected, the evaluator shall verify that the TSS
                identifies the key derivation method, the AES-based key wrapping method, the secret
                value encapsulation technique, and the random number generator. <h:br/>
              <Guidance/> None. 
              <Tests/> 
              For each supported key transport schema, the evaluator shall initiate at least 25
              sessions that require key transport with an independently developed remote instance
              of a key transport entity, using known RSA key-pairs. The evaluator shall observe
              traffic passed from the sender-side and to the receiver-side of the TOE, and shall
              perform the following tests, specific to which key transport scheme was employed.
              If the KTS-OAEP scheme was selected, the evaluator shall perform the following
              tests:
              1. The evaluator shall inspect each cipher text, C, produced by the RSA-OAEP
              encryption operation of the TOE and make sure it is the correct length, either
              256 or 384 bytes depending on RSA key size. The evaluator shall also feed into
              the TOE’s RSA-OEAP decryption operation some cipher texts that are the
              wrong length and verify that the erroneous input is detected and that the
              decryption operation exits with an error code.
              2. The evaluator shall convert each cipher text, C, produced by the RSA-OAEP
              encryption operation of the TOE to the correct cipher text integer, c, and use the
              decryption primitive to compute em = RSADP((n,d),c) and convert em to the
              encoded message EM. The evaluator shall then check that the first byte of EM
              is 0x00. The evaluator shall also feed into the TOE’s RSA-OEAP decryption
              operation some cipher texts where the first byte of EM was set to a value other
              than 0x00, and verify that the erroneous input is detected and that the decryption
              operation exits with an error code.
              3. The evaluator shall decrypt each cipher text, C, produced by the RSA-OAEP
              encryption operation of the TOE using RSADP, and perform the OAEP
              decoding operation (described in NIST SP 800-56B section 7.2.2.4) to recover
              HA’ || X. For each HA’, the evalutor shall take the corresponding A and the
              specified hash algorithm and verify that HA' = Hash(A). The evaluator
              shall also force the TOE to perform some RSA-OAEP decryptions
              where the A value is passed incorrectly, and the evaluator shall verify
              that an error is detected.
              4. The evaluator shall check the format of the ‘X’ string recovered in OAEP.Test.3
              to ensure that the format is of the form PS || 01 || K, where PS consists of zero or
              more consecutive 0x00 bytes and K is the transported keying material. The
              evaluator shall also feed into the TOE’s RSA-OEAP decryption
              operation some cipher texts for which the resulting ‘X’ strings do not have the
              correct format (i.e., the leftmost non-zero byte is not 0x01). These incorrectly 
              formatted ‘X’ variables shall be detected by the RSA-OEAP decrypt
              function.
              5. The evaluator shall trigger all detectable decryption errors and validate that the
              returned error codes are the same and that no information is given back to the
              sender on which type of error occurred. The evaluator shall also validate that no
              intermediate results from the TOE’s receiver-side operations are revealed to the
              sender.
              If the KTS-KEM-KWS scheme was selected, the evaluator shall perform the
              following tests:
              1. The evaluator shall inspect each cipher text, C, produced by RSA-KEM-KWS
              encryption operation of the TOE and make sure the length (in bytes) of the
              cipher text, cLen, is greater than nLen (the length, in bytes, of the modulus of
              the RSA public key) and that cLen - nLen is consistent with the byte lengths
              supported by the key wrapping algorithm. The evaluator shall feed into the
              RSA-KEM-KWS decryption operation a cipher text of unsupported length and
              verify that an error is detected and that the decryption process stops.
              2. The evaluator shall separate the cipher text, C, produced by the sender-side of
              the TOE into its C0 and C1 components and use the RSA decryption primitive to
              recover the secret value, Z, from C0. The evaluator shall check that the
              unsigned integer represented by Z is greater than 1 and less than n-1, where n is
              the modulus of the RSA public key. The evaluator shall construct examples
              where the cipher text is created with a secret value Z = 1 and make sure the
              RSA-KEM-KWS decryption process detects the error. Similarly, the evaluator
              shall construct examples where the cipher text is created with a secret value Z =
              n – 1 and make sure the RSA-KEM-KWS decryption process detects the error.
              3. The evaluator shall attempt to successfully recover the secret value Z, derive the
              key wrapping key, KWK, and unwrap the KWA-cipher text following the RSAKEM-KWS
              decryption process given in NISP SP 800-56B section 7.2.3.4. If the
              key-wrapping algorithm is AES-CCM, the evaluator shall verify that the value
              of any (unwrapped) associated data, A, that was passed with the wrapped keying
              material is correct The evaluator shall feed into the TOE’s RSA-KEM-KWS
              decryption operation examples of incorrect cipher text and verify that a
              decryption error is detected. If the key-wrapping algorithm is AES-CCM, the
              evaluator shall attempt at least one decryption where the wrong value of A is
              given to the RSA-KEM-KWS decryption operation and verify that a decryption
              error is detected. Similarly, if the key-wrapping algorithm is AES-CCM, the
              evaluator shall attempt at least one decryption where the wrong nonce is given to
              the RSA-KEM-KWS decryption operation and verify that a decryption error is
              detected.
              4. The evaluator shall trigger all detectable decryption errors and validate that the
              resulting error codes are the same and that no information is given back to the
              sender on which type of error occurred. The evaluator shall also validate that no
              intermediate results from the TOE’s receiver-side operations (in particular, no Z
              values) are revealed to the sender.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="FCS_KDF_EXT.1" name="Cryptographic operation (Key Derivation)">
          <selection-depends req="FCS_KYC_EXT.1.1" ids="USEKEYDER"/>
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FCS_KDF_EXT.1.1">
            <title>
              The TSF shall accept 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>a RNG generated submask as specified in FCS_RBG_EXT.1</selectable>
                <selectable>a conditioned password</selectable>
                <selectable>an imported submask</selectable>
              </selectables> to derive an intermediate key, as defined in [selection:
             <selectables>
               <selectable>NIST SP 800-108 
                 <selectables>
                   <selectable>KDF in Counter Mode</selectable>
                   <selectable>KDF in Feedback Mode</selectable>
                   <selectable>KDF in Double-Pipeline Iteration Mode</selectable>
                 </selectables>
               </selectable>
               <selectable>NIST SP 800-132</selectable>
             </selectables> using the keyed-hash functions specified in FCS_COP.1(4), such that the output is at least of
              equivalent security strength (in number of bits) to the FEK.
            </title>
            <note role="application">This requirement is used in the body of the ST if the ST author chooses to
              use key derivation in the key chaining approach that is specified in FCS_KYC_EXT.1.
              This requirement establishes acceptable methods for generating a new random key or an
              existing submask to create a new key along the key chain.</note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/>
              The evaluator shall verify the TSS includes a description of the key derivation
                function and shall verify the key derivation uses an approved derivation mode and
                key expansion algorithm according to SP 800-108 and SP 800-132. <h:br/>
              <Guidance/> None. 
              <Tests/> None. 
              </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="FCS_COP.1(7)" name="Cryptographic operation (Key Encryption)">
          <selection-depends req="FCS_KYC_EXT.1.1" ids="USEKEYENC"/>
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FCS_COP.1.1(7)">
            <title>
              The TSF shall 
              <selectables>
                 <selectable>use platform-provided functionality to perform Key Encryption</selectable>
                 <selectable>perform [key encryption and decryption] in accordance with a specified cryptographic algorithm [AES used in CBC mode] and cryptographic key sizes 
                  <selectables linebreak="yes">
                    <selectable>128</selectable>
                    <selectable>256</selectable>
                  </selectables> bits that meet the following:
                  [AES as specified in SP 800-38A.]
                 </selectable>
             </selectables>
            </title>
              <note role="application">This requirement is used in the body of the ST if the ST author chooses to
                use AES encryption/decryption for protecting the keys as part of the key chaining approach
                that is specified in FCS_KYC_EXT.1.</note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/>
              <h:h4>Requirement met by the platform</h:h4> If the platform provides the FEK
              encryption/decryption, then the evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it
              describes how the FEK encryption/decryption is invoked. <h:br/>
              <h:h4>Requirement met by the TOE</h:h4> The evaluator shall verify the TSS includes a description of the key size used for
              encryption and the mode used for the key encryption <h:br/>
              <Guidance/> None. 
              <Tests/> 
              The evaluation activity tests specified for AES in CBC mode in FCS_COP.1.1(1) in
 the underlying Application Software PP shall be performed.
              </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="FCS_COP.1(5)" name="Cryptographic operation (Key Wrapping)">
          <selection-depends req="FCS_KYC_EXT.1.1" ids="USEKEYWRA"/>
          
          <consistency-rationale>
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element id="FCS_COP.1.1(5)">
            <title>
              The TSF shall 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>use platform-provided functionality to perform Key Wrapping</selectable>
                <selectable>implement functionality to perform Key Wrapping </selectable>
              </selectables> in accordance with a specified cryptographic algorithm [AES] in the following modes
                  <selectables linebreak="yes">
                    <selectable>Key Wrap</selectable>
                    <selectable>Key Wrap with Padding</selectable>
                    <selectable>GCM mode</selectable>
                    <selectable>CCM mode</selectable>
                  </selectables> and the cryptographic key size 
                  <selectables>
                    <selectable>128 bits (AES)</selectable>
                    <selectable>256 bits (AES)</selectable>
                  </selectables> that meet the following: 
                  <selectables linebreak="yes">
                    <selectable>“NIST SP 800-38C”</selectable>
                    <selectable>“NIST SP 800-38D”</selectable>
                    <selectable>“NIST SP 800-38F”</selectable>
                    and no other standards.
                  </selectables>
            </title>
            <note role="application">This requirement is used in the body of the ST if the ST author chooses to
              use key wrapping in the key chaining approach that is specified in FCS_KYC_EXT.1.</note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS/> or KMD (Key Management Description may be used if necessary details describe proprietary information)
              <h:h4>Conditional:</h:h4> If use platform provided functionality was selected, then the evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it
              describes how the FEK encryption/decryption is invoked. <h:br/>
              
              <h:h4>Conditional:</h:h4> If impliment functionality was selected, The evaluator shall check that the TSS includes
              a description of encryption function(s) used for key wrapping. The evaluator should check that this description of the
              selected encryption function includes the key sizes and modes of operations as specified in the selection above.
              The evaluator shall check that the TSS describes the means by which the TOE satisfies constraints on algorithm parameters
              included in the selections made for ‘cryptographic algorithm’ and ‘list of standards’. 
              
              The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that the points at which key wrapping and decryption occurs are described,
              and that the complete data path for key wrapping is described. The evaluator checks that this description is consistent
              with the relevant parts of the TSS.
              
              Assessment of the complete data path for key wrapping includes confirming that the TSS describes the data flow from the
              device’s host interface to the device’s non-volatile memory storing the data. 
              
              
              <h:br/>
              <Guidance/> If multiple encryption modes are supported, the evaluator examines the guidance documentation
              to determine that the method of choosing a specific mode/key size by the end user is described.
              
              <Tests/> 
              The evaluation activity tests specified for AES in GCM mode in the underlying Application Software PP shall be performed in the case that "GCM" is selected in the requirement.
              
              If AES Key Wrap is used to decrypt/encrypt the key, the evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine that it specifies that the implementation conforms to SP 800-38F with the appropriate (with or without padding) Key Wrap section using AES. 
              The evaluator shall also perform the verification procedures outlined in the testing methodology, "The Key Wrap Validation System." (http://csrc.nist.gov/groups/STM/cavp/documents/mac/KWVS.pdf)
              
              AES-CCM Tests
              These tests are intended to be equivalent to those described in the NIST document, “The CCM Validation System (CCMVS),” updated 9 Jan 2012, found at http://csrc.nist.gov/groups/STM/cavp/documents/mac/CCMVS.pdf.
              
              It is not recommended that evaluators use values obtained from static sources such as 
              http://csrc.nist.gov/groups/STM/cavp/documents/mac/ccmtestvectors.zip
              or use values not generated expressly to exercise the AES-CCM implementation.
              
              The evaluator shall test the generation-encryption and decryption-verification
              functionality of AES-CCM for the following input parameter and tag lengths:
              Keys: All supported and selected key sizes (e.g., 128, 256 bits).
              Associated Data: Two or three values for associated data length: The minimum (≥ 0 bytes) and maximum (≤ 32 bytes) supported associated data lengths, and 2^16 (65536) bytes, if supported.
              Payload: Two values for payload length: The minimum (≥ 0 bytes) and maximum (≤ 32 bytes) supported payload lengths.
              Nonces: All supported nonce lengths (7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13) in bytes.
              Tag: All supported tag lengths (4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, 16) in bytes.
              
              The testing for CCM consists of five tests. To determine correctness in each of the below tests, the evaluator shall compare the ciphertext with the result of encryption of the same inputs with a known good implementation.
              
              Variable Associated Data Test
              For each supported key size and associated data length, and any supported payload length, nonce length, and tag length, the evaluator shall supply one key value, one nonce value, and 10 pairs of associated data and payload values, and obtain the resulting ciphertext.
              
              Variable Payload Text
              For each supported key size and payload length, and any supported associated data length, nonce length, and tag length, the evaluator shall supply one key value, one nonce value, and 10 pairs of associated data and payload values, and obtain the resulting ciphertext.
              
              Variable Nonce Test
              For each supported key size and nonce length, and any supported associated data length, payload length, and tag length, the evaluator shall supply one key value, one nonce value, and 10 pairs of associated data and payload values, and obtain the resulting ciphertext.
              
              Variable Tag Test
              For each supported key size and tag length, and any supported associated data length, payload length, and nonce length, the evaluator shall supply one key value, one nonce value, and 10 pairs of associated data and payload values, and obtain the resulting ciphertext.
              
              Decryption-Verification Process Test
              To test the decryption-verification functionality of AES-CCM, for each combination of supported associated data length, payload length, nonce length, and tag length, the evaluator shall supply a key value and 15 sets of input plus ciphertext, and obtain the decrypted payload. Ten of the 15 input sets supplied should fail verification and five should pass.
              
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
    </sel-sfrs>
    
    <obj-sfrs></obj-sfrs>
    
    <!--  
    This chapter describes the security requirements
    which have to be fulfilled by the file encryption client. Those requirements comprise functional
    components from Part 2 of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>. The following notations are used: <h:ul>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Selection</h:b> (denoted by <h:i>italicized text</h:i>): is used to select one or more options
        provided by the [CC] in stating a requirement.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Assignment</h:b> operation (denoted by <h:i>italicized text</h:i>): is used to assign a
        specific value to an unspecified parameter, such as the length of a password. Showing the
        value in square brackets indicates assignment.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Iteration</h:b> operation: are identified with a number inside parentheses (e.g.
        "(1)").</h:li>
    </h:ul>
    
    <section title="Security Functional Requirements for the File Encryption Application (TOE)"
      id="SFRs"> As indicated in Section 1.3.2, security functional requirements in the main body of
      the PP-Module are divided into those that must be satisfied by the file encryption application (the
      TOE), and those that must be satisfied by either the TOE or the platform on which it runs.
      This section contains the requirements that must be met by the TOE.   
      
      
    </section>
    
    -->
  </chapter>

<!--  
  <appendix title="Optional Requirements" id="optional" >
    As indicated in <secref linkend="ccl"/>, the baseline requirements (those that must be
    performed by the <abbr title="Target of Evaluation" linkend="TOE">TOE</abbr>) are contained in the body of this PP.
    Additionally, there are three other types of requirements specified in 
    <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and
    <appref linkend="objective"/>.
    The first type (in this Appendix) are requirements that can be included in the <abbr title="Security Target" linkend="ST">ST</abbr>,
    but are not required in order for a TOE to claim conformance to this PP. The second type 
    (in <appref linkend="sel-based"/>)
    are requirements based on selections in the body of the PP: if certain selections are made,
    then additional requirements in that appendix must be included. The third type (in
    <appref linkend="objective"/> are components that are not required in
    order to conform to this PP, but will be
    included in the baseline requirements in future versions of this PP, so adoption by
    vendors is encouraged. Note that the ST author is responsible for ensuring that
    requirements that may be associated with those in 
    <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and
    <appref linkend="objective"/>
    but are not listed (e.g., FMT-type requirements) are also included in the ST.
  </appendix>
  
  <appendix title="Selection-Based Requirements" id="sel-based" >
    As indicated in the introduction to this PP, the baseline requirements (those that must be
    performed by the TOE or its underlying platform) are contained in the body of this PP. There
    are additional requirements based on selections in the body of the PP: if certain selections are
    made, then additional requirements below will need to be included.
  </appendix>
  
  <appendix title="Objective Requirements" id="objective">
    This Annex includes requirements that specify security functionality which also addresses
    threats. The requirements are not currently mandated in the body of this PP as they describe
    security functionality not yet widely available in commercial technology. However, these
    requirements may be included in the ST such that the TOE is still conformant to this PP, and
    it is expected that they be included as soon as possible.
  </appendix>
  -->

    <bibliography>
      <entry id="bibCC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - <h:ul>
          <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                1: Introduction and General Model</h:a>, CCMB-2017-04-001, Version 3.1 Revision 5,
              April 2017.</h:li>
          <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                2: Security Functional Components</h:a>, CCMB-2017-04-002, Version 3.1 Revision 5,
              April 2017.</h:li>
          <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                3: Security Assurance Components</h:a>, CCMB-2017-04-003, Version 3.1 Revision 5,
              April 2017.</h:li>
          </h:ul></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibAppPP">
        <tag>AppPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/pp/">Protection Profile for Application Software</h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="FIPS140-2">
        <tag>FIPS140-2</tag>
        <description> Federal Information Processing Standard Publication (FIPS-PUB) 140-2, Security
          Requirements for Cryptographic Modules, National Institute of Standards and Technology,
          March 19, 2007 </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="FIPS180-4">
        <tag>FIPS180-4</tag>
        <description> Federal Information Processing Standards Publication (FIPS-PUB) 180-4, Secure
          Hash Standard, March, 2012 </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="FIPS186-4">
        <tag>FIPS186-4</tag>
        <description> Federal Information Processing Standard Publication (FIPS-PUB) 186-4, Digital
          Signature Standard (DSS), National Institute of Standards and Technology, July 2013
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="FIPS197">
        <tag>FIPS197</tag>
        <description>Federal Information Processing Standards Publication (FIPS-PUB) 197,
          Specification for the Advanced Encryption Standard (AES), November 26, 2001 </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="FIPS198-1">
        <tag>FIPS198-1</tag>
        <description>Federal Information Processing Standards Publication (FIPS-PUB) 198-1, The
          Keyed-Hash Message Authentication Code (HMAC), July 2008 </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="SP800-38A">
        <tag>NIST800-38A</tag>
        <description>NIST Special Publication 800-38A, Recommendation for Block Cipher Modes of
          Operation: Methods and Techniques, 2001 Edition </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="SP800-56A">
        <tag>NIST800-56A</tag>
        <description>NIST Special Publication 800-56A, Recommendation for Pair-Wise Key
          Establishment Schemes Using Discrete Logarithm Cryptography (Revised), March 2007
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="SP800-56B">
        <tag>NIST800-56B</tag>
        <description>NIST Special Publication 800-56B, Recommendation for Pair-Wise Key
          Establishment Schemes Using Integer Factorization Cryptography, August 2009 </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="SP800-90">
        <tag>NIST800-90</tag>
        <description>NIST Special Publication 800-90, Recommendation for Random Number Generation
          Using Deterministic Random Bit Generators (Revised), March 2007 </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="SP800-132">
        <tag>NIST800-132</tag>
        <description>NIST Special Publication 800-132, Recommendation for Password-Based Key
          Derivation, December 2010 </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="SP800-38F">
        <tag>NIST800-38F</tag>
        <description>NIST Special Publication 800-38F,Recommendation for Block Cipher Modes of
          Operation: Methods for Key Wrapping, December 2012 </description>
      </entry>
    </bibliography>
  
    <acronyms>
      <entry>
        <term>AES</term>
        <description>Advanced Encryption Standard</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CC</term>
        <description>Common Criteria</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>CM</term>
        <description/>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>FAK</term>
        <description>File Authentication Key</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>FEK</term>
        <description>File Encryption Key</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>DRBG</term>
        <description>Deterministic Random Bit Generator</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>EAL</term>
        <description>Evaluation Assurance Level</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ECC</term>
        <description>Elliptic Curve Cryptography</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ECC CDH</term>
        <description>Elliptic Curve Cryptography Cofactor Diffie-Hellman (see NIST SP 800-56A rev 2,
          section 6.2.2.2)</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>FIPS</term>
        <description>Federal Information Processing Standards</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ISSE</term>
        <description>Information System Security Engineers</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>IT</term>
        <description>Information Technology</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>KDF</term>
        <description>Key Derivation Function</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>KEK</term>
        <description>Key Encryption Key</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PBKDF</term>
        <description>Password-Based Key Derivation Function</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PIN</term>
        <description>Personnel Identification Number</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PKI</term>
        <description>Public Key Infrastructure</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PP</term>
        <description>Protection Profile</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>PUB</term>
        <description>Publication</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>RBG</term>
        <description>Random Bit Generator </description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SAR</term>
        <description>Security Assurance Requirement</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SF</term>
        <description>Security Function</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>SFR</term>
        <description>Security Functional Requirement</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>ST</term>
        <description>Security Target</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>TOE</term>
        <description>Target of Evaluation</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>TSF</term>
        <description>TOE Security Functionality</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>TSFI</term>
        <description>TSF Interface</description>
      </entry>
      <entry>
        <term>TSS</term>
        <description>TOE Summary Specification </description>
      </entry>
    </acronyms>
  
</Module>
